<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 14:06:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Tips for Organizing Electronic Files</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-digital-files/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 14:06:23 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-digital-files/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-digital-files/ -&lt;p&gt;After having to work with many electronic files during my years in the IB, I developed my own file organization method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;naming&#34;&gt;Naming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-it-meaningful&#34;&gt;Make It Meaningful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give your files &lt;strong&gt;meaningful names&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s very likely that you need to revise your essay draft multiple times, so you can&amp;rsquo;t really tell which draft is the final one until you get close to submission. So don&amp;rsquo;t just call it &lt;em&gt;final&lt;/em&gt;, and then the revised version &lt;em&gt;real final&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;real final final&lt;/em&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done that. That&amp;rsquo;s really funny, but that&amp;rsquo;s not helpful for identifying the content of each file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, try something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft 1&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft with conclusion modified&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or &lt;em&gt;draft with neat formatting&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the changes are hard to summarize, so I use things that happen to me while I&amp;rsquo;m working on the file to name it. For example, &lt;em&gt;draft after history test&lt;/em&gt;. In this way, the name helps me remember the day I have worked on the file as well as the content I edited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the two naming methods above don&amp;rsquo;t work, I name the file using the time I finish the draft. The &amp;ldquo;last modified date&amp;rdquo; in operating systems gets renewed every time even when there&amp;rsquo;s only one slightest change in the file, but I only want to track the major changes. So, I record the time on my own, like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;draft on monday evening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;notes at late sunday night&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Docs, Sheets and Slides can basically do these for you with the function for tracking changes. You can also very conveniently name the history versions. But I believe there&amp;rsquo;re people out there who sometimes just don&amp;rsquo;t want to work with those editing tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaningful names can be very helpful when you search for files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;perfection&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perfection&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a perfectionist, so I had been naming files and folders with my best consistency and my best attention to capitalization and spaces or underscores between words, before I realized that naming files &amp;ldquo;perfectly&amp;rdquo; wastes loads of time. &lt;strong&gt;Pressing &amp;ldquo;Shift&amp;rdquo; at the start of almost every single word can be more tiring and time-consuming than one thinks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I name files with lowercase letters, and sometimes, I use hyphens to replace underscores and spaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;del&gt;An Example File Name.doc&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;an-example-file-name.doc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former makes sense—typing lowercase is easier. There are several reasons to the latter one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate escaping every single space in terminal or command prompt, or whatever you call it. Well, technically you can also &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;type the file name within parenthesis just like this.txt&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. This is more about one&amp;rsquo;s personal preference. But when it comes to putting files onto the web (like what I do here on my blog), hyphens are helpful because they work perfectly in URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Chinese file names, it&amp;rsquo;s so much easier. I just smash everything together and use a hyphen whenever I need to separate the characters. Because of the shapes of characters, any numbers and Latin alphabet letters can stand out clearly from Chinese characters, which is very convenient when I look for files by the file names. Some real examples are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020-05-11P1答卷小说-捅马蜂窝.pdf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;毕业典礼全过程（我的片段带字幕）压缩版.mp4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structuring-info&#34;&gt;Structuring Info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a &lt;strong&gt;consistent structure&lt;/strong&gt; for the file names, and &lt;strong&gt;order the parts of a file name to help you look for specific files&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I had a lot of files for data processing when I did my physics EE experiment. I had 7 different materials to work with (so 7 data points), each with 3 trials, and each trial included 2 types of measurements, each in a different file. So I named them like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 1 - Angle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 1 - Length&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 2 - Angle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 2 - Length&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 3 - Angle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandpaper Trial 3 - Length&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rubber Trial 1 - Angle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rubber Trial 1 - Length&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order of information is the same: material, trial, and measurement. The order can also help categorize the files so that I can search from a wide range and narrow down to a file, which is next to other similar files that I might want to look at at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your file name &lt;strong&gt;can really be ordered to help you&lt;/strong&gt; though. Names that start with dates like &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;29 Jan 2021&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;17 Feb 2021&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; are less helpful than those with &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;2021-01-19&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;2021-02-07&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Because the former format can be ordered like a mess:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1 June 2021.txt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;6 Dec 2020.txt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;17 Feb 2021.txt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;29 Jan 2021.txt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-it-short&#34;&gt;Make It Short&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the names &lt;strong&gt;as short as possible, but make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t forget what your abbreviations mean&lt;/strong&gt;. In this way, you can scan through your folders faster and find the file you want faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;physics ia presearch - pendulum experiment trial 1 video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;physics ia presearch - pendulum research paper a real pendulum vs simple pendulum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;physics ia - pendulum worksheet with experiment design draft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might want to try this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;trial 1 vid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;real vs simple pendulum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;experiment design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is much less overwhelming and much easier for humans to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hotkeys&#34;&gt;Hotkeys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpful to know the hotkeys for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &amp;amp; Paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-select (with &lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jump to start / end / next word / next paragraph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jump to file by the first letter in its name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close current window (&lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Cmd&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open new folder / finder window (&lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Cmd&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working a lot with electronic files, I slowly realized that &lt;strong&gt;anything task that can be completed using a keyboard can go much faster than things that you have to do using a mouse&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You only have one mouse and one cursor to go around the whole screen, but you have 10 fingers (that&amp;rsquo;s 10 times more!) that can stretch across the whole keyboard, which is usually no larger than your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;views&#34;&gt;Views&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the purpose, &lt;strong&gt;different views of files in folders / finder&lt;/strong&gt; can have different effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List view is helpful when you search by file name or when there&amp;rsquo;re a lot of files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Icon view is helpful for searching among images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop-down lists are helpful when you need to search among the subfolders of multiple folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also find it helpful to see the file extensions. So it&amp;rsquo;s much easier for me to distinguish between different files with similar names, especially the editable versions and the exported &amp;ldquo;locked&amp;rdquo; versions. So instead of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021-03-10 Homework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021-03-10 Homework&lt;/em&gt; ,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the file types shown in a different column in the folder / finder window,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021-03-10 Homework.pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021-03-10 Homework.pdf&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;re probably more to explore depending on your file viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;automation&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For MacOS users, &lt;strong&gt;Automator&lt;/strong&gt; is a great helper for many repetitive tasks. It can bulk copy files, resize pictures, combine PDFs, rename files, replace parts of file names with a given string, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know programming, you can even do more with apple scripts (in Automator), python, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s not complicated at all. Even just a GUI automation package for python can do a lot for you, but that&amp;rsquo;s really brute forcing things haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Windows, an equivalent software is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autohotkey.com/&#34;&gt;AutoHotkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although the lack of a graphical UI might make it a bit more intimidating than the &amp;ldquo;drag and drop&amp;rdquo; interface in Automator. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it, so can&amp;rsquo;t say much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are computers for? What are they good at? Repetitive tasks! So let them do the job for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;backup&#34;&gt;Backup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing backups is easy. Don&amp;rsquo;t risk losing your files. Simply weigh up the risks and effort required from you, and the correct choice should be clear. &lt;strong&gt;Although the risk of losing files seems low, but once it happens, barely anything can save you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-story&#34;&gt;My Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a personal story. Last week, my laptop got stuck in the system update process, and it turned out that the only way to make it work was to clear the whole storage. What&amp;rsquo;s in there? All my coursework, electronic notes, research resources, pictures, videos, browser bookmarks, diary, blog post drafts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I used to copy my important files onto an external hard drive from time to time, and I did that again before the system update. So what got lost was the unimportant ones, although I still put a lot of time into creating them and organizing them in nice folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only can you lose the personal documents, but also the personalization settings, tools, etc. For example, I lost the handy tools I wrote with python and bash. I lost the personalized hotkeys. I also lost the plug-ins I added bits by bits to chrome, atom and typora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the lesson. Do backups regularly, and do complete backups. But how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-advice&#34;&gt;Some Advice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copying files onto an external hard drive, like what I did, is the most basic form of creating backups. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt some rules from here and there, which seem quite convincing to me. An idea is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keepitsafe.com/blog/post/3-2-1-rule-for-cloud-backup/&#34;&gt;3-2-1 backup rule&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;re other more advanced methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the 3-2-1 backup rule is that you need to &lt;strong&gt;have multiple copies in multiple places (geographical location) and in multiple forms of storage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I have my IB DP Chinese paper 1 practice locally on my laptop, on my external hard disk, online in my Google Drive, and as hard copies at home. (Unfortunately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t kept all my files in this way before I attempted to update my laptop. )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These copies can virtually guarantee the safety of these files, even when, for example, an earthquake happens near my house and destroys everything. Or when something&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; like in Liu Cixin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Ball Lightning&lt;/em&gt; happens in real life 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another idea is to work, as often as possible, with cloud service, and download your files regularly to keep a local copy of everything. Like Google Drive, MS OneDrive, GitHub, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time machine and iCloud are useful for MacOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And always be careful and remember to do a backup before you make any major changes to your laptop, or any electronic device. They are not as reliable as they seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I agree with it when people say that the more simple a storage media is, the more it is controllable by you.&lt;/strong&gt; Controllable in the sense that your data can be preserved as you wish, and in the sense that your data is exposed to others as you wish. A bit off the topic, but this is exactly one of the reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m still keeping a physical diary book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the helpful tips as far as I know now. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to share your experience and tips in the comment section, and you can also find contact info under the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;ldquo;Backups&amp;rdquo; section, I talked about having copies in different forms of storage, which include hard copies on paper. So, I&amp;rsquo;m planning to talk about &lt;strong&gt;organizing physical files&lt;/strong&gt; in next week&amp;rsquo;s update, more or less with an emphasis on my experience as a student. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to avoid spoilers. &lt;em&gt;Ball Lightning&lt;/em&gt; is an awesome sci-fi novel. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32076670-ball-lightning&#34;&gt;An English translation&lt;/a&gt; of the work exists.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-digital-files/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My IB DP Chinese Lit P1 Homework</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/my-chn-a-lit-p1-hw/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 09:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/my-chn-a-lit-p1-hw/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/my-chn-a-lit-p1-hw/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do 😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../zh/posts/my-chn-a-lit-p1-hw/&#34;&gt;我的 IB DP 中文文学试卷一作业&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed! If you have any questions or suggestions, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me via email! (You can find the contact details at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For next week&amp;rsquo;s update, I&amp;rsquo;m planning to write about &lt;strong&gt;some random but helpful skills for the DP and for life in general&lt;/strong&gt;, which I found out about in the past two years of studying. Stay tuned 😉&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/my-chn-a-lit-p1-hw/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My Experience &amp; Tips for IB Textbooks: Chinese A Lit SL</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do 😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;../../../zh/posts/ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl/&#34;&gt;我的 IB 课本使用心得：中文 A 文学 SL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: Updates</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 17:57:28 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/ -&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a week without any update. The reason is that, I found out with fear and worries that blogging seemed to become a burden instead of an enjoyable hobby for me. When I focused on finishing the series on &lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl&#34;&gt;textbooks&lt;/a&gt;, I slowly fell into a trap that I dug for myself—I narrowed my mind to simply doing work and couldn&amp;rsquo;t escape from the whirlpool of endless tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I gave myself a break. It felt so good that I could have time to do things other than blogging. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give up on blogging. I want to continue. I want to become active in writing and expressing ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like writing my diary, because I see it as a record of my &amp;ldquo;personal history&amp;rdquo; which lets me see myself in the past and gain insights and power from the past experiences. For me, this blog is similar, although compared to my diary, my blog has less personal things but more formal and organized content. Also, more or less, my blog has things targeting at my readers. Yet after all, my diary and blog are quite similar. Both of them let me enjoy the time being alone, and let me enjoy the &amp;ldquo;inner&amp;rdquo; thoughts and activities, those arising from my own mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I can always enjoy blogging, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to be more casual with it. The things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been saving and wanting to write about this whole time, no matter aiming at myself or my readers, I will still probably write about. However, I want to keep &lt;strong&gt;myself&lt;/strong&gt; as a part of my audience.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My Experience &amp; Tips for IB Textbooks: Chemistry SL</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:55:04 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 4th post in my blog series called &amp;ldquo;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips for IB Textbooks&amp;rdquo;. The IB subjects covered in this series are DP Physics, Math AA, Chemistry, History, and Chinese A Lit. The corresponding levels and syllabus versions (years of first assessment) are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Level&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Other Posts in This Series&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Physics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Math AA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chemistry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This article&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;History&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-history-sl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chinese A Lit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are the IB DP subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve studied. I&amp;rsquo;ve used at least 2 textbooks (or study guides) for each of these subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the &lt;strong&gt;Chemistry&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks that I&amp;rsquo;ve used. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the textbooks by their publishers, compare and contrast their features, their strengths and weaknesses (in my opinion), and finally give my thoughts on how to use textbooks. All the information here is for reference only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This article is really short, so there&amp;rsquo;s no TL;DR.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbook-reviews&#34;&gt;Textbook Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these two years of DP, I used a total of 2 textbooks from 2 publishers. Because Chemistry is only an SL subject for me and the IB sciences have always been alright for me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t put so much effort into learning it. So I&amp;rsquo;ll just briefly talk about the books below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pearson-education&#34;&gt;Pearson Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Higher Level Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2nd ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Catrin Brown, Mike Ford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-447-95975-5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-chemistry-tb/pearson-chemistry-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Higher Level Chemistry, published by Pearson Education&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an SL version of this book, but I used the HL version. Even though, all the chapters and sections in this book have the corresponding IB syllabus topic numbers, so it&amp;rsquo;s very clear which sections are SL content and which are HL content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Chemistry for the IB Diploma Coursebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2nd ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Steve Owen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-107-62270-8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-chemistry-tb/cambridge-chemistry-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Chemistry for the IB Diploma Coursebook, published by Cambridge University Press&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book suits both the SL and HL course. Its SL and HL content is separated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;compare--contrast&#34;&gt;Compare &amp;amp; Contrast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The form of these two books are similar to the Physics textbook published by their respective publisher. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can look at the relevant sections in my previous articles for reference. Links: &lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl/#pearson-education&#34;&gt;Pearson&amp;rsquo;s Physics textbook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl/#cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s Physics textbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pearson&amp;rsquo;s book has a &lt;strong&gt;tighter&lt;/strong&gt; formatting, while Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s formatting is &lt;strong&gt;looser&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s totally a matter of personal preference when deciding which one is better. But surprisingly, &lt;strong&gt;Pearson&amp;rsquo;s book is much thicker than Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/strong&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s relatively harder to finish reading it as well as to carry it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the loose formatting, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;better emphasis on key points in Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, all the important definitions (words, phrases &amp;amp; sentences), formulas and equations are all in red text boxes. Whereas Pearson usually only has the key words in bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice problems in these two books are &lt;strong&gt;similar&lt;/strong&gt;. Both of them have exercises after each section and a more comprehensive problem set after each chapter. The comprehensive sets also have a wide range of problems, including multiple choice and free response questions, which are all in the IB style. But I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;re any IB past paper questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s book says which problems in the comprehensive sets are for HL only, so that&amp;rsquo;s pretty friendly for SL students to use. Because I learned the SL course using Pearson&amp;rsquo;s HL textbook, naturally, the book didn&amp;rsquo;t categorize the problems so clearly. Of course, you&amp;rsquo;re free to opt for Pearson&amp;rsquo;s SL textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The styles of explanation in these two books are pretty different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pearson&amp;rsquo;s book covers &lt;strong&gt;wider&lt;/strong&gt; content, so there&amp;rsquo;re more explanations. Those include some background information, such as the general naming of elements, the relationship between stoichiometry and other chapters and how learning stoichiometry helps us learn chemistry. Those also include some specific case studies. For example, when the book explains hydrogen bonds in the chapter for intermolecular forces, it explains why although the density of most substances increases when they change from solids to liquids, the density of ice is less than that of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s book is &lt;strong&gt;more concise&lt;/strong&gt; and it goes &lt;strong&gt;deeper&lt;/strong&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;re many extensions in this book, which when compared to Pearson&amp;rsquo;s content, help us more with deepening our understanding of the course content. For example, this book explains why grahpite works as a lubricant, and why the electronegativity of Cl and N is the same but there&amp;rsquo;s no hydrogen bond when there&amp;rsquo;s only Cl-H. It also explains why bond-forming is exothermic with reference to potential energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to choose one from them, I would choose the Cambridge book. Because it explains the reasoning behind the key points it talks about. As in my example in the last paragraph, although it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to remember H–F, H–N, and H–O as the three scenarios for forming hydrogen bonds, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain why only these cases work. I feel uncertain and even gets a bit annoyed when there&amp;rsquo;re gaps in what I learn. The extra information in Pearson&amp;rsquo;s book is interesting, and to some extent, it could be helpful for exam, but I&amp;rsquo;d rather wish that I understand things more deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional Materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pearson&amp;rsquo;s ebook has lab instructions and those are very helpful, but it seems like that the paper copy doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the ebook and you need to purchase it separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Cambridge &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/go/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;re useful lab instructions, too. You just need to register for free and select this textbook from the database before you can download the instructions. Additionally, there&amp;rsquo;re more downloadable materials on the website. (They&amp;rsquo;re not so important though.) It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that the Cambridge Chemistry textbook doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many additional practice problems online like the Cambridge Physics and Math textbooks do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-textbooks&#34;&gt;Using the Textbooks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that although these two books are different, &lt;strong&gt;one isn&amp;rsquo;t clearly better than the other&lt;/strong&gt;. Because these two books have different emphasis in their explanations, I recommend using them like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you have time, use both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you don&amp;rsquo;t have time, I recommend you use the Cambridge book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some clarification here. If you read both of them, you can pick a random one to read carefully and skim through the other one. Read one carefully first, and then read the other one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to do the problems, just do whatever you want. The practice problems in these two books are similar and both pretty good anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I think, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have time but still want to learn things and improve your grade, then Pearson&amp;rsquo;s book is really a bit long and some of its relatively general content like the background information isn&amp;rsquo;t very useful practically. Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s book is shorter, and the helpful and suitable extensions can also help you memorize a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I talked about 2 &lt;strong&gt;Chemistry&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks for the 2016 IB DP syllabus. The books are published by Pearson and Cambridge respectively. Based on my own learning experience, compared and contrasted them side by side while trying to reference concrete examples, and at the end, I gave some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt; for using textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still updating this series of blog posts, and I&amp;rsquo;ll post links to the new updates in the table at the beginning of this blog post. Feel free to check them out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover any specific chemistry study methods, such as tricks for memorization. I will mention those in future blog posts. But &lt;strong&gt;next week&amp;rsquo;s update will probably be on DP Chinese A Literature textbooks and study guides or DP History revision methods&lt;/strong&gt;. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short-Term Revision: It&#39;s Okay!</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term revision method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My personal experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenarios suitable for applying this article&amp;rsquo;s method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exam preparation, namely, to improve grades, but not to better your grasp of knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tight schedule (within about a month before the exam?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plenty of free time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;0-cramming-and-i-some-unimportant-words&#34;&gt;0. &amp;ldquo;Cramming&amp;rdquo; and I: Some Unimportant Words?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a procrastinator, so for many exams, even though I had time to prepare, I still ended up doing short-term preparation, aka cramming. Some examples include my IELTS exam, a math competition (which I don&amp;rsquo;t want to name here), and almost every History mock exam. But my grades were acceptable, at least much better than if I didn&amp;rsquo;t revise at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many exams, even if I got prepared to some extent, when I came to the moment right before the exam, I still revised intensively. For example, I did that for almost all the mock exams (especially the chemistry ones) during these two years in IB DP. Also, I think cramming was actually helpful for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I cram a lot, and the process has been painful. I often regret that I didn&amp;rsquo;t use my everyday learning to avoid this pain of cramming. However, every single time, I felt &lt;strong&gt;extremely lucky&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;thankful&lt;/strong&gt; of myself for really devoting my time to cramming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always say: Don&amp;rsquo;t cram. I think that makes sense, because we want to form the good habit of learning bits by bits and building up our knowledge gradually, and in this way the knowledge is surely more complete and more longstanding. Cramming is in sharp contrast with this. But, I also think that&amp;rsquo;s not to shame us for cramming when we have no other solution. As I see it, &lt;strong&gt;cramming shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be something so unforgivable&lt;/strong&gt;. It should be a neutral term; it should only be a temporary solution to our problems—it lets us secure our grades first, and then we can really catch up with the knowledge. As long as grades are an important measurement of our academic performance, I guess, for us who are in endless competitions, cramming will still be a need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also understand that, &lt;strong&gt;the need to cram sometimes does not mean that we&amp;rsquo;re always going to rely on cramming in our revision&lt;/strong&gt;. When we cram, there isn&amp;rsquo;t any extra time for us to use as a backup, so we need our revision plan to go without any disruptions, which I think is highly risky in itself. After all, to stress it again, I think of cramming only as a temporary solution to our problems. I believe that efficient and effective studying is necessarily based on sufficient studying time and good everyday habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-mentally-prepare-yourself&#34;&gt;1. Mentally Prepare Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself: &lt;strong&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s time left. Why don&amp;rsquo;t I use that to revise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most important thing is to acknowledge the current reality and stay rational. The time before the exam will only get shorter, so we should try hard to spend every single second on revision, &lt;strong&gt;not on being anxious&lt;/strong&gt;. Another reason for us to calm down is that, only when we have a clear mind, our efficiency can improve. Don&amp;rsquo;t blame yourself too much or have too much stress and anxiety. Of course, don&amp;rsquo;t let things go and give up on yourself, either. Keep a stable state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to know what we should do, so that we can make a plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-sacrifice-some-content&#34;&gt;2. Sacrifice Some Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself: &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m already at this stage, so I must sacrifice things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closely study the exam requirements, look at the past papers, and &lt;strong&gt;after you get some understanding of them&lt;/strong&gt;, skip the unnecessary content for your revision, but &lt;strong&gt;make sure that you can still gain marks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the month before my IB DP Finals, I started to get more and more free time, and at the same time, I needed to revise for History&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Luckily, meanwhile, because of COVID, the content of History paper 2 for the M21 exam session is reduced from writing two essays from different topics to writing only one essay. That means, although we learned two topics, we didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to revise both of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I needed to know clearly: Which topic should I revise? Which case studies for this topic should I revise? Every topic has three sub-topics. Should I revise all three of them, or should I make a choice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, I wanted to revise all of them: both topics, all sub-topics, all the case studies. But soon I realized that my time was too little for the large amount of content, so I had to give up on a lot of content and take some risks. In the end, I weighed up the different choices like below and made my decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Problem&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Some Considerations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Decision&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Which topic?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I learned 20th Century Wars in a messy way, and I can&amp;rsquo;t find so much historiography&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revise Topic 10: Authoritarian States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Which case studies?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany is also part of the content for paper 1, overlapping with paper 2; Paper 2 might ask for cases from two different regions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revise Germany &amp;amp; China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Which sub-topics?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Almost every exam covered only two sub-topics, with each question corresponding to a sub-topic&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; The latter two sub-topics are more closely connected with each other than with the first one&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revise the latter two sub-topics: &lt;em&gt;Consolidation &amp;amp; Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, I sacrificed a lot of knowledge content to make up for the depth of my revision, while making sure that at least one question on paper 2 would be from the ones that I prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the exam is held regularly and consecutively, then &lt;strong&gt;we can definitely find, more or less, some patterns in the exam questions&lt;/strong&gt;. We should also make use of these patterns, although we can&amp;rsquo;t rely on them too much. For example, the exam questions of IB DP History rarely repeat, so I studied the past paper questions carefully and found out that some key points, such as foreign policy, weren&amp;rsquo;t tested yet under the current syllabus. So when I revised for other key points, I also put emphasis on these things. Surprisingly, in the exam, there was actually a question specifically on foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-know-the-form&#34;&gt;3. Know the Form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself: &lt;strong&gt;If I can do work before the exam to save time during it, even if I only save a minute, that&amp;rsquo;s still my gain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Familiarize yourself with the form of your exam materials, such as exam paper(s), data/formula booklet, and calculator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layout &amp;amp; Formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Font type, font size, paper size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location of key info, such as description of content on exam papers, key words in questions, key formulas in formula booklets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numbering: Page number of exam papers, numbering of sources (if applicable), question numbers, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meaning of letters in formula booklets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculator functions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &amp;amp; paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To enter an often-used value quickly, define it as $x$ or any letter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Order of variables in the normal distribution function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are what you need to &amp;ldquo;cram&amp;rdquo;. &lt;strong&gt;Familiarizing yourself with the exam materials is also part of exam preparation&lt;/strong&gt;. Only when we know the exam environment, we can relax more when we apply our knowledge and save the time we might spend on familiarizing with the paper and looking for information on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, before my exam, I dedicated time to familiarize myself with DP History paper 1, which I think was really worth it. During that time, I realized that on paper 1, under the heading of each prescribed subject, there was a description of the content covered in that specific exam. So I knew that I must look at that first to avoid going off topic later in my answers to the questions. I also found out that some questions, such as the OPVL questions, always have the same beginning. Only the second half of the question is the specific requirements for this time. So during the exam, I could go directly for the second half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-plan-your-revision&#34;&gt;4. Plan Your Revision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself: &lt;strong&gt;If I don&amp;rsquo;t do the most important things first, am I waiting to run out of time so I have to simply give up?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use your time effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prioritize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hardest &amp;amp; the most important content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best revision resources &amp;amp; the newest past papers (or IB specimen/example papers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;not necessary to do a lot of papers now&lt;/strong&gt;. Doing one or two sets of the most valuable (usually the newest) exam papers completely should suffice. For the rest, simply read each question, annotate it, think, have an answer in your mind, and then look at the mark scheme. Save your time for writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I did this in the morning before my DP Physics exam. I read each question directly, came up with a direction or a method, and if it&amp;rsquo;s in the mark scheme, then I could skip this question. Only if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t come up with a direction to work in or if my method was different from the syllabus, then I worked on the question carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to practice time management during the actual exam, especially for essay-writing questions, then I recommend you plan to do past papers or similarly styled mock papers at a later stage of your revision, under exam conditions. At this later stage, your&amp;rsquo;ve already mastered the majority of content, so now you can just focus on application of knowledge and the more practical things, such as how much time you need to spend on each essay paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I only completed a hand-written paper-2 essay at the night before my History exam, not any earlier during my revision. In this way, I could apply the knowledge I revised when I wrote by hand and that really have me a sense of achievement and boosted my confidence. I think this positive mindset was very helpful for me who had been in a &amp;ldquo;cramming mode&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell myself: &lt;strong&gt;During these days of exam preparation, I&amp;rsquo;m just a emotionless problem-solving machine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only when there&amp;rsquo;s a plan, we can complete our work in an organized manner. But we&amp;rsquo;re already prepping in the short-term, so it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;not necessary to write out a overly-detailed plan&lt;/strong&gt;. Our brain&amp;rsquo;s memory can handle that anyway. The only thing to do is to know what we need to revise and how much progress we ideally want at what point in time. In the days of revision, all activities should be based on the revision plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when I revised for History, I wanted to finish the outlines for all the possible essay titles—so that&amp;rsquo;s what I need to revise—in 2 to 3 days. Then, I needed to come up with a plan like this (at least in my mind):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Key Point in Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ideal Progress&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;End of Day 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finish &lt;em&gt;Consolidation &amp;amp; Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;End of Day 2 Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Memorize the finished outlines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;End of Day 2 Evening&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finish &lt;em&gt;Policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;End of Day 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finish anything remaining, memorize all the outlines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last days of my revision, I was also actually learning History all day long. I only followed my revision plan and didn&amp;rsquo;t care about anything else. Because I already made up my mind: I have to prepare well for the History final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;online-resource&#34;&gt;Online Resource&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. By 史東183, an uploader on Bilibili. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty long—19 minutes long, so might be good if you have some mechanical, repetitive tasks to do when you watch (or listen to) it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link:&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Up411Z7Ns?share_source=copy_web&#34;&gt;〔Shi Dong〕I&amp;rsquo;m so stressed about the college entrance exam that I&amp;rsquo;m getting bald. How can I keep my mind at ease?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I learned from the video was &lt;strong&gt;active learning&lt;/strong&gt;. This means, when you revise in the short-term, don&amp;rsquo;t even think about making beautiful, neat, and perfect notes. Instead, do problems and learn while you apply knowledge. But it&amp;rsquo;s a bit different from what I found to be suitable for me after trial and error. See this article&amp;rsquo;s last section &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;./#my-experience&#34;&gt;My Experience&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; for the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;strong&gt;there are some differences between the short-term revision that I talked about in this article and other preparation before exams&lt;/strong&gt;. I should be able to write another article later to talk about those other things. But, &lt;strong&gt;next week&amp;rsquo;s update should be on DP Chemistry textbooks which is in the series &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl/#introduction&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips for IB Textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope my 4-step short-term revision method can give you some reference. I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;../../about/#my-ib-experience&#34;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; of this blog&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo;, I described in details the History course content at my school.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debatable for N19.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video is in Mandarin Chinese, without subtitles.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original title: 〔史东〕高考压力大到头秃，怎麽保持平常心？&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My Experience &amp; Tips for IB Textbooks: History SL</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 18:33:54 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 3rd post in my blog series called &amp;ldquo;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips for IB Textbooks&amp;rdquo;. The IB subjects covered in this series are DP Physics, Math AA, Chemistry, History, and Chinese A Lit. The corresponding levels and syllabus versions (years of first assessment) are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Level&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Other Posts in This Series&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Physics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Math AA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chemistry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;History&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This article&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chinese A Lit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are the IB DP subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve studied. I&amp;rsquo;ve used at least 2 textbooks (or study guides) for each of these subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the &lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks that I&amp;rsquo;ve used. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the textbooks by their publishers, compare and contrast their features, their strengths and weaknesses (in my opinion), and finally give my thoughts on how to use textbooks. All the information here is for reference only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note that the History syllabus was slightly revised after 2017, and the latest version has the first year of assessment of 2020. But the revision is pretty much negligible, so none of the textbooks I will mention later updated due to this change.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; is at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbook-reviews&#34;&gt;Textbook Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend much time learning History, during the final revision, I still put in a lot of effort and used 4 books from 2 publishers which cover World History Topic 10 (Authoritarian States) and Prescribed Subject 3 (The Move to Global War). The case studies in topic 10 that I focused on are China (1949-76) and Germany (1933-45), so my reviews are generally based on these parts of the textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t deny that my insight on the History textbooks is probably shallower than that on Physics and Math AA textbooks, because it&amp;rsquo;s an SL subject and I only prioritized it for a couple of weeks during revision. So do keep this in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hodder-education&#34;&gt;Hodder Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;p2-textbook&#34;&gt;P2 Textbook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-history-tb/hodder-topic-10-tb.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Access to History for the IB Diploma: Authoritarian states, published by Hodder Education&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;(Taken from the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Access to History for the IB Diploma: Authoritarian states&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2nd Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Michael Lynch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-1-4718-3930-6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The textbook above is for &lt;strong&gt;Paper 2, World History Topic 10: Authoritarian States&lt;/strong&gt;. The case studies are USSR (1924-53), Germany (1933-45), China (1949-76), Egypt (1952-70), Cuba (1959-2006), Argentina (1946-74) and Tanzania (1961-85).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow the IB syllabus very closely. It seems like that this book &lt;strong&gt;still goes with a topic called &amp;ldquo;Authoritarian and Single-Party States&amp;rdquo; in the old syllabus (first assessment in 2010)&lt;/strong&gt;, but it has added some new content like foreign policies in accordance with the new syllabus. These two syllabi are similar, but the style and content of essay questions can differ a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, under the big theme of domestic policies, the old syllabus includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;political, economic, social and religious policies [and their impact,]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but the new syllabus includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aims and impact of domestic economic, political, cultural and social policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new syllabus, it&amp;rsquo;s totally possible that the IB asks about the extent to which some domestic policies achieved their aims  (as they did in N18), but that&amp;rsquo;s not explicitly in the old syllabus. Nor was &amp;ldquo;cultural policies&amp;rdquo;, which is in the new syllabus, included explicitly in the old syllabus. However, this book &lt;strong&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly discuss cultural policies or aims of domestic policies&lt;/strong&gt; in Hitler&amp;rsquo;s Germany as it should for the new syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section titles in this book also follow the old syllabus. For example, when it talks about the governmental system, the book&amp;rsquo;s subheading is &amp;ldquo;the structure and organization of government&amp;rdquo; instead of something like &amp;ldquo;domestic political policies&amp;rdquo; which is the wording in the new syllabus. Not to mention that the emphasis of the new syllabus also changed a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For History, any subtle change in the emphasis or wording of an essay question can greatly affect the targeted answer. So it&amp;rsquo;s better to have a textbook that is tailored directly at the latest syllabus, the latest question types, and organized in the same way as the syllabus requirements. Regarding syllabus coverage, this book&amp;rsquo;s issue is pretty serious, so &lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend using this textbook as your only textbook&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Content: Description, Explanation &amp;amp; Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the chapter on Germany was much better than the chapter on China. For the latter, &lt;strong&gt;some paragraphs are unnecessarily long, descriptive, and narrative, while some important events are not elaborated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example is the section on domestic economic policies in China. I only found two sentences (page 139) on agricultural collectivization before 1958, and almost only a name-dropping of the First Five-Year Plan. There&amp;rsquo;s no mention of any concrete industrial project. And there&amp;rsquo;s even more omissions on other subtopics—no mention of Gao Gang and Rao Shushi, no mention of &lt;em&gt;Hai Rui Dismissed from Office&lt;/em&gt; as a possible trigger of the Cultural Revolution, and no mention of educational reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the book describes (or probably more accurately, imagines) vividly how participants at Lushan Conference were afraid of Mao. It also pictures, imaginatively, the Backyard Furnaces—&amp;ldquo;the sky glowed red at night as families everywhere endeavoured to produce steel in homemade kilns&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in my opinion, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more helpful content on Germany. There&amp;rsquo;re clear descriptions and explanations, as well as evidence-based evaluation, although the conclusions of its evaluation should be examined carefully as historians always do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historiography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book includes &lt;strong&gt;very good historiographical debates&lt;/strong&gt;. At the end of almost every case study, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole section on different perspectives. There&amp;rsquo;s even a separate chapter for comparing and contrasting Nazism, Communism and Maoism and for the related debates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essay-Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book &lt;strong&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t give enough guidance on essay-writing&lt;/strong&gt;. It explains the steps towards writing an essay, and it includes many exam practice questions, but there&amp;rsquo;s only 1 exemplar essay which only uses the case studies of China and Germany. So actually, it&amp;rsquo;s only helpful if your school happens to teach these case studies. Even that, there&amp;rsquo;s only one example essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the book walks the reader through the whole process by giving an outline first, and the annotations do point out what&amp;rsquo;s good in the essay, which is quite nice. But the process seems to take too long so it&amp;rsquo;s not so realistic for exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;p1-textbook&#34;&gt;P1 Textbook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-history-tb/hodder-pres-4-tb.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Access to History for the IB Diploma: The move to global war, published by Hodder Education&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;(Taken from the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Access to History for the IB Diploma: The move to global war&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 1st Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Andy Dailey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-1-4718-3932-0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The textbook above is for &lt;strong&gt;Paper 1, Prescribed Subject 3: The Move to Global War&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good. Organization of content matches the syllabus. Every key point in the syllabus is elaborated. Much much better than Hodder&amp;rsquo;s P2 textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;the balance between case studies isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect&lt;/strong&gt;. The syllabus suggests that Italy and Germany should have the same weight, but this book seems to focus more on Germany—Italy takes about half a chapter, and Germany takes a whole chapter. Especially the economic factors for Italian expansion were relatively vague. For that, I had to look at the section for Mussolini&amp;rsquo;s Italy in &lt;a href=&#34;./#cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s P2 textbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Content: Description, Explanation &amp;amp; Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear account of events, with &lt;strong&gt;extracts from primary and secondary sources&lt;/strong&gt; to further illustrate key points and to give a wider context. For example, Mussolini&amp;rsquo;s quote &amp;ldquo;war is to man what maternity is to a woman&amp;rdquo; clearly pictures the fascist ideology and the resulting aggressive foreign policy then seems natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book makes &lt;strong&gt;helpful connections&lt;/strong&gt; between events when explaining why and when things happen. Only until I read this book, I realized that Italy could invade Albania in 1939 with little foreign opposition because of its previous victories and dominant position over Yugoslavia and Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book also gives a timeline after each case study, as well as a &lt;strong&gt;diagram connecting all the events&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of each section, which I found helpful. The Hodder P2 textbook also has similar diagrams, but I think they are more helpful for this topic (the move to global war), because on paper 1 we need to focus more on the events instead of debates like on paper 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is &lt;strong&gt;a bit short on evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, evaluation of the importance of factors contributing to Japanese expansion. It does list out many factors, such as the Great Depression, conflict between the military and the civil government, ultra-nationalism and belief in the manifest destiny. The book also explains how these factors led to expansion. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t weigh them up. So if you use this book, you need to look at the evidence and make your own judgments on the factors&#39; importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exam Guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of guidance and practice questions on exams. At the end of every chapter, there&amp;rsquo;s one or two sections on exams which explain the techniques for each type of question and make use of the chapter&amp;rsquo;s content to form example questions. Then, the book walks the reader through the example questions and gives exemplar answers with annotations, comments, and grading. Finally, there&amp;rsquo;re two sets of practice questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the interpretation of visual sources, the book talks about symbolism, captions, and it applies the skills to posters, cartoons, stamps and photos. This was especially helpful for my exam preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem is that, except for the example questions, none of the practice questions have answers or question-specific mark schemes attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;p1-study-guide&#34;&gt;P1 Study Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-history-tb/hodder-pres-4-study-guide.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Access to History for the IB Diploma: The move to global war Study and Revision Guide, published by Hodder Education&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;(Taken from the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Access to History for the IB Diploma: The move to global war Study and Revision Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 1st Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Andy Dailey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-1-5104-3234-5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study guide above is for &lt;strong&gt;Paper 1, Prescribed Subject 3: The Move to Global War&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covers the syllabus perfectly. Same as Hodder&amp;rsquo;s P1 textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Content: Description, Explanation &amp;amp; Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically a condensed version Hodder&amp;rsquo;s P1 textbook. All the course content is organized in exactly the same order, but with more bullet points and fewer explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open the book, the page on the left has the course content, and the one on the right has exercises and guidance for exams. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use the exercises on the right page, but the short bullet points on the left page worked well as quick summaries. When the Hodder textbook explains, for example, the Meiji Constitution with several paragraphs, this study guide just out the most important points—clear and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exam Guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of exam guidance. At the end of each chapter, there&amp;rsquo;re two sets of complete paper 1s. One is &lt;strong&gt;with student answers&lt;/strong&gt;, grading and comments. The other one is &lt;strong&gt;for your own practice&lt;/strong&gt; and there are mark schemes at the back of the study guide. The student answers include good and bad ones, so you can really see exactly what the IB likes and doesn&amp;rsquo;t like. These extra practice papers can be extremely valuable because the number of past papers is relatively small and most of them have sources removed because of copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All the exercises have answers&lt;/strong&gt; at the back, too. So you can revise on your own. This is much better than the other two Hodder books that I mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-history-tb/cambridge-topic-10-tb.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of History for the IB Diploma Paper 2 Authoritarian States (20th Century), published by Cambridge University Press&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;(Taken from Lehmanns Media&amp;rsquo;s website)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;History for the IB Diploma Paper 2 Authoritarian States (20th Century)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2nd Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Allan Todd, Sally Waller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-1-107-55889-2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The textbook above is for &lt;strong&gt;Paper 2, World History Topic 10: Authoritarian States&lt;/strong&gt;. The case studies are Italy under Mussolini, Germany under Hitler, China under Mao, and Cuba under Castro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to this textbook as I write this blog post, so I can&amp;rsquo;t give many specific examples. But I probably used this textbook for the longest—I used it everyday, from morning to evening, during my final days of revision, so I do remember some details in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good. Content is organized according to the syllabus, and each section is led by a question reworded from the syllabus requirements. This makes makes the learning objectives crystal clear. I think Cambridge revised their old textbook better than Hodder did before publishing it for the new syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hodder P2 textbook doesn&amp;rsquo;t have Italy so this book is good if you study that, but this book has fewer case studies (e.g No USSR). Here&amp;rsquo;s a table comparing the case studies in these two textbooks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Hodder Only&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Both&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cambridge Only&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Italy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tanzania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Egypt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cuba&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Argentina&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Content: Description, Explanation &amp;amp; Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might seem brief and insufficient, but after using it for a while, I think the amount of information in this book is &lt;strong&gt;just right for this course&lt;/strong&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find key events omitted from this book, as I did for the chapter on China in the Hodder P2 textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the book tells you full events. For example, it says China became more reliant on Canadian food imports after the Great Leap Forward, and it says that the Hundred Flowers Campaign ended with the Anti-Rightist Campaign. These are all left out of the Hodder P2 textbook, making the reader wonder what the aftermath was but can&amp;rsquo;t learn about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I like about this book is that it &lt;strong&gt;makes judgments&lt;/strong&gt; on, for example, the success of cultural policies. Its judgment was that in both China and Germany, during the authoritarian rule, old culture was destroyed but new culture was not created. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter so much if it&amp;rsquo;s correct; at least the book gives us something to think about and to add into the historians&#39; perspectives in our essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historiography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historiographical debates are scattered throughout the text, so finding them can be harder than in the Hodder P2 textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But exactly because they are scattered throughout, they are always incorporated into the discussion of specific sub-topics. That&amp;rsquo;s helpful for the reader to learn how to incorporate perspectives organically into the exam essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essay-Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of helpful guidance. At the back of the book, there&amp;rsquo;re 3 example essays with annotations, grading and comments. The book also color-codes the good and bad parts in the essays, to show exactly where marks are awarded or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these are more helpful than Hodder&amp;rsquo;s P2 example, because of several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The length of these essays is &lt;strong&gt;more manageable under exam conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The types of essay questions are more varied—asking for 1 case study, as well as comparing and contrasting 2 case studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall examiner comments tend to be more specific and constructive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it still &lt;strong&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a perfect-scoring example&lt;/strong&gt; which has a length manageable under exam conditions. This is really frustrating as I found this problem to be very common for sources providing example P2 essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-books&#34;&gt;Using the Books&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation works the best for final revision, because that&amp;rsquo;s my experience, but I think the case should be similar for everyday learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For efficiency, I recommend using Hodder&amp;rsquo;s P1 Study Guide first. Only when you can&amp;rsquo;t tell the connection behind Study Guide&amp;rsquo;s bullet-point summaries, or when you can&amp;rsquo;t think of any related historical context, you read the Hodder P1 textbook carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want P1 practice but have finished all the past papers, then I recommend that you go for the full practice papers in the Study Guide. The questions in the Hodder P1 textbook and the exercises in the Study Guide can help, but the former doesn&amp;rsquo;t have answers and the latter aren&amp;rsquo;t always in IB-style, so they&amp;rsquo;re less helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For History, the more you read, or the more perspectives and facts you know, the better. So although I don&amp;rsquo;t think Hodder&amp;rsquo;s textbook is great for learning new content, it can be helpful for revision and additional content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I recommend using Cambridge as the main textbook, and then Hodder as a supplement. When learning Germany, you can actually use both, but when learning China, it&amp;rsquo;s probably better to focus on the Cambridge book. I&amp;rsquo;m yelling inside that &lt;strong&gt;you should never use the Hodder P2 textbook for China&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s a personal opinion after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I talked about 4 &lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; books for the 2021 IB DP syllabus. Three of them are published by Hodder and one is published by Cambridge. I listed out their &lt;strong&gt;features&lt;/strong&gt;, compared and contrasted the &lt;strong&gt;strengths and weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt; of each of them in my mind. Throughout the process, I tried to reference to concrete examples. At the end, based on my own learning (or revision) experience, I gave some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt; for using textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still updating this series of blog posts, and I&amp;rsquo;ll post links to the new updates in the table at the beginning of this blog post. Feel free to check them out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover any specific tips for studying IB History, such as exam and revision skills. I will mention these in future blog posts. For more posts on History, please use the &amp;ldquo;tabs&amp;rdquo; function on the sidebar of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have different opinions or more insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;options-covered&#34;&gt;Options Covered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prescribed Subject 3: The Move to Global War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World History Topic 10: Authoritarian States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-features-of-each-book&#34;&gt;Main Features of Each Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Book&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;General Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Exam Guidance&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hodder P1 Textbook&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Very good, with minor problems&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clear, helpful connections &amp;amp; explanations; Little evaluation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Many helpful tips; No answers to practice questions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hodder P1 Study Guide&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Same as above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Concise; Condensed version of the book above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Many full practice papers; All answers provided&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper 2 (Table 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Publisher&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Syllabus Coverage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;General Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Historiography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Essay-Writing&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hodder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not so good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Confusing for China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Separated from other content&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guidance okay; 1 example&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cambridge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brief, but complete and helpful; With evaluation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scattered throughout text&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detailed, realistic guidance; 3 examples&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper 2 (Table 2: Case studies covered by each P2 textbook)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Hodder Only&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Both&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cambridge Only&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Italy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tanzania&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Egypt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cuba&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Argentina&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-way-of-using-the-books&#34;&gt;Recommended Way of Using the Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Mainly intended for revision and exam preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick revision: Read the Hodder P1 Study Guide;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling gaps: Read the Hodder P1 textbook;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice: Do past papers first, then do the complete papers in the Hodder P1 Study Guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main textbook: Cambridge (Especially when studying China—don&amp;rsquo;t use Hodder for that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplement: Hodder P2 textbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My Experience &amp; Tips for IB Textbooks: Math AA HL</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:42:01 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the 2nd post in my blog series called &amp;ldquo;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips for IB Textbooks&amp;rdquo;. The IB subjects covered in this series are DP Physics, Math AA, Chemistry, History, and Chinese A Lit. The corresponding levels and syllabus versions (years of first assessment) are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Level&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Other Posts in This Series&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Physics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-physics-hl/&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Math AA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This article&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chemistry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-chemistry-sl/&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;History&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-history-sl/&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chinese A Lit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../ib-tb-review-chinese-a-lit-sl&#34;&gt;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are the IB DP subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve studied. I&amp;rsquo;ve used at least 2 textbooks (or study guides) for each of these subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the &lt;strong&gt;Math AA&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks that I&amp;rsquo;ve used. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the textbooks by their publishers, compare and contrast their features, their strengths and weaknesses (in my opinion), and finally give my thoughts on how to use textbooks. All the information here is for reference only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; is at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbook-reviews&#34;&gt;Textbook Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think good Math textbooks and good Physics textbooks are actually pretty similar. They both need to have these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good practice problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me talk about the Math textbooks I&amp;rsquo;ve used. In the two years of DP, I used 3 textbooks from 2 publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;haese-mathematics&#34;&gt;Haese Mathematics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-math-tb/haese-math-core-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Mathematics: Core Topics HL, published by Haese Mathematics&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title：&lt;em&gt;Mathematics: Core Topics HL&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition：1st Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors：Michael Haese, Mark Humphries, Chris Sangwin, Ngoc Vo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-925489-58-3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As suggested by the title, this book covers the common content of AA and AI HL, as well as a very small amount of content which is AI-only and unrelated to AA at all. Some of the content in this book only scratches the surface, and the more in-depth parts are in the following textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-math-tb/haese-math-aa-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Mathematics: Analysis and Approaches HL, published by Haese Mathematics&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title：&lt;em&gt;Mathematics: Analysis and Approaches HL&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition：1st Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors：Michael Haese, Mark Humphries, Chris Sangwin, Ngoc Vo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-925489-59-0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As suggested by the title, this books covers the AA-HL-only content which is left out of the first book. The two books above are in the same series and should be used together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book series splits up the syllabus content of AA HL, with a small portion in Book 1 and this large remaining portion in Book 2, creating a sharp cut-off. For example, the first book deals with the transformation of functions superficially, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover absolute-value transformation, square transformation, rational functions with quadratics, and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s not until Book 2 that all the transformations required in the syllabus are covered. If you&amp;rsquo;re sure you want to learn AA HL from the beginning and have not thought about AI HL, then Haese&amp;rsquo;s sectioning of the book really makes little sense and is somewhat confusing. But that can be helpful if you&amp;rsquo;re still trying to decide between AA and AI HL at the start of DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is divided into chapters so carefully that it takes almost every small point in the syllabus and puts it into a subsection. This is best illustrated by the fact that the book singles out logistic functions as a subsection under the chapter on differential equations. However, logistic functions are only one example of the curriculum when illustrating differential equations with separable variables. Although there is no harm in studying logistic functions in depth, and that did deepen my understanding of differential equations and partial fractions, still, sometimes the focus of the book is a bit hard to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I feel that there are so many chapters in this book, and they are so finely divided! For example, this book uses 4 or 5 chapters to talk about derivative calculus. Another example is chapter 12—Vectors in Book 2. This series of books separates vectors in 2D and 3D, but it&amp;rsquo;s totally possible to combine the content, because&amp;hellip; aren&amp;rsquo;t vectors in 2D just vectors in 3D with z-coordinates equal to zero? 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;re many things in this set that are not in the IB syllabus, such as checking for function continuity, derivability, and permutations in which some elements are repeated. When using this set of books, keep in mind that you should always follow the syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanations are detailed, but a bit rigid. The explanation of Euler&amp;rsquo;s method in the chapter on differential equations gave my biggest headache. This book comes up directly to say that &amp;ldquo;at each iteration of Euler&amp;rsquo;s method, we generate another point for our solution curve&amp;rdquo;, but the readers don&amp;rsquo;t even know the specifics of Euler&amp;rsquo;s method, so when they see the word iteration, they&amp;rsquo;ll only get lost, won&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the style of explanation in this book is a bit like that in the Chinese high school math textbook (2007 edition) published by People&amp;rsquo;s Education Press (PEP), where concepts are often introduced through quick examples and then directly followed by formulas and problems, although Haese&amp;rsquo;s book has more textual explanations. This style is not bad, but Haese&amp;rsquo;s proofs are usually not as detailed as that of PEP&amp;rsquo;s textbook. An example is the proof for the distributive law in vector dot products. Haese uses exercises to let the readers come up with the proof themselves, but the full proof is not included in the answers at the end of the book. So, while the book is not completely free of proofs, if you want to see complete proofs, then that&amp;rsquo;s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably for the IB&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;international understanding&amp;rdquo;, this textbook includes a lot of content on the history of mathematics. While it is actually quite interesting, and we should really learn more or less about the development of mathematics in the world, the content is laid out in a standard format that is mixed in with the explanations in the book, rather than as separate sections, which makes it confusing. While for TOK, there are separate sections in this book series, which makes it feel clearer and more reader-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The e-version of the book also has step-by-step audio and visual explanations for each example problem. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this self-tutoring function much, but if you prefer someone to explain the book out loud instead of reading it yourself, then this might be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of practice problems, and I think they are all original. There&amp;rsquo;re practice problems after each section, and two sets of comprehensive review questions of different difficulty at the end of each chapter. However, these questions do not mimic the IB question style and often have less step-by-step guidance than the IB ones, so they&amp;rsquo;re relatively more difficult. But when you have enough free time, it&amp;rsquo;s also helpful to look at different types of questions to open up your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest edition of this book series comes with three sets of trial exam papers targeting IB P1, P2, and P3, and it also includes some additional practice questions for P3. Nonetheless, there are still some problems. The P1 and P2 questions are still more difficult than typical IB questions, and the P3 questions seem to have more content per question than the IB ones, so time will be tighter. However, these questions can be used as additional revision material while you go through the IB past papers. Especially, the P3 practice questions in these sets can be helpful, given how limited the past papers are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The e-book is very convenient, and it allows you to take notes and use the online tools, such as the data analysis tool and the graphing tool. I really like the online simulations that come with this book, especially the one for conic sections that is introduced as an extension when starting quadratic functions. Seeing 3D cones being cut by a plane on the computer is really more helpful than drawing it yourself on paper and imagining it in your head, and it&amp;rsquo;s also so much easier than making the cones and cuts by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/ib-math-tb/cambridge-math-tb.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Mathematics for the IB Diploma: Higher Level, published by Cambridge University Press&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title：&lt;em&gt;Mathematics for the IB Diploma: Higher Level&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition：2012 Ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors：Paul Fannon, Vesna Kadelburg, Ben Woolley, Stephen Ward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-107-66173-8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was written for the old Math HL syllabus, which was first assessed in 2014, and instead of writing a new textbook for the new syllabus, Cambridge has made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/us/files/4315/7962/0788/IB_Mathematics_Analysis_and_Approaches_mapping.pdf&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; that maps the content in the new syllabus with the chapters in the old textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the book is not divided into chapters for the new syllabus, each chapter corresponds to almost every section of requirements in the new syllabus. The chapters are also clearer than Haese&amp;rsquo;s, because the book is not arbitrarily divided into two books, as Haese has done, making the content fragmented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, this book does not contain unnecessary details. I mentioned how Haese had different sections for vectors in 2D and 3D, so here&amp;rsquo;s another example: this book does not separate &amp;ldquo;3D geometry without vectors&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;3D geometry with vectors&amp;rdquo; as Haese has done. For AA HL, Haese&amp;rsquo;s division is not necessary at all. And this book categorizes chapters into broad topics like algebra, equations and functions, geometry, calculus, statistics and probability, while Haese does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also has a summary for each chapter, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it much because I personally don&amp;rsquo;t find it very helpful to read other people&amp;rsquo;s summaries. But this is indeed what&amp;rsquo;s missing from Haese&amp;rsquo;s textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book originally targeted the old syllabus, so there&amp;rsquo;re inevitably extra or missing sections in it when you study the new syllabus. Note that most of the calculus content in the new syllabus comes from the optional calculus chapters in the old syllabus, while the optional chapters of this book are only included in the e-book on the CD at the back of the paper copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanations in this book are usually very natural, which I personally feel to be better than Haese. For example, the explanation of Euler&amp;rsquo;s method in the chapter on differential equations. The book starts by drawing jagged lines, walking the reader slowly through the steps of Euler&amp;rsquo;s method, visually illustrating the knowledge and then summarizing it in a more mathematically rigorous way. At least for me, this makes it easier to learn new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes me feel comfortable using this book is that it has many accompanying proofs, both fill-in-the-blank versions and completed ones. Moreover, it has some proofs that are not in Haese&amp;rsquo;s textbook, such as the formula $Var(X)=np(1-p)$ for the variance of the binomial distribution $X\sim{B(n,p)}$ , as well as the product rule for differentiation. However, these proofs are included in the e-book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough practice problems. Overall, I found the problems in this book more suitable for exam preparation than Haese&amp;rsquo;s, although they are not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are exercises after each section, with non-IB style questions to familiarize you with the concepts, as well as IB style questions. Each chapter is followed by a more comprehensive problem set, and there is even a special  chapter to provide problems that crosses topics. These include both long and short response questions in the IB style. There are also free chapter tests available on the Cambridge &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/go/resources/Mathematics-for-the-IB-Diploma-Higher-Level&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, which can be accessed by registering for a free account. These problems are in the IB style and are similar in difficulty to those in IB exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book also color codes all the questions in green, blue, and red to indicate the difficulty and type of questions, and also shows the calculator requirements, which was very helpful when I did problems for revision, while Haese does not have these features. The e-book also comes with more Extension worksheets, but not in the IB style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book doesn&amp;rsquo;t have complete trial exam papers and mark schemes like Haese does, so that&amp;rsquo;s a con. But it&amp;rsquo;s not a big problems, because you can always make up for it by doing the real IB exam papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, this book doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with trial exam papers, but its online materials include more, like assessment papers for each chapter. Its e-book has many additional things, too, such as proofs (fill-in and completed versions), extension worksheets, supplementary materials, self-discovery sheets, etc. The e-book also has problems related to prior learning, which I think is helpful for you to check for gaps before you start the DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has some drawbacks though. Its e-book is not on cloud so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t update or correct the mistakes automatically. The e-book is simply a collection of PDF documents, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have math tools or simulations like Haese&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-textbooks&#34;&gt;Using the Textbooks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because neither of the textbooks I mentioned above cover the IB syllabus perfectly, I recommend you use the syllabus itself as your first reference source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best way of using textbooks is like this. When you learn, you look at the syllabus first, and then look at the explanations in both textbooks together (but look at Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s explanation first). Later, you can use Haese&amp;rsquo;s problems and Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s non-IB-style problems to quickly familiarize yourself with the new concepts. To solidify your knowledge, you can use Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s IB-style problems. And for exam preparation (mainly at the final stage of IB DP), you can use Haese&amp;rsquo;s trial exam papers and Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s IB-style problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If both books cover a topic, I prefer to read the Cambridge explanation first because it is more natural, and then I read Haese&amp;rsquo;s explanation to check for gaps. However, this is only a personal preference, and there are some topics in the new syllabus that only appear in Haese&amp;rsquo;s textbook, such as augmented matrices in linear algebra. During the past two years of DP, when studying some topics, although I only read Haese&amp;rsquo;s explanations and not Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any difficulties or have any major problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t used the &lt;a href=&#34;(https://global.oup.com/education/product/9780198427162/?region=international)&#34;&gt;Math AA textbook published by Oxford University Press&lt;/a&gt;, so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on it here. But maybe it covered the IB syllabus better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I talked about 2 &lt;strong&gt;Math AA&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks for the 2021 IB DP syllabus. The books are published by Haese and Cambridge respectively. I listed out their &lt;strong&gt;features&lt;/strong&gt;, compared and contrasted the &lt;strong&gt;strengths and weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt; of each of them in my mind. Throughout the process, I tried to reference to concrete examples. At the end, based on my own learning experience, I gave some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt; for using textbooks. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that this article did not include the Oxford textbook, which is similarly quite mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still updating this series of blog posts, and I&amp;rsquo;ll post links to the new updates in the table at the beginning of this blog post. Feel free to check them out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover any specific math study methods, such as how to organize problems you did wrong, nor does it cover specific tips for studying IB Math, such as exam skills. All of these I will mention in future blog posts. For more posts on the IB DP course, Math AA, or on math, please use the &amp;ldquo;tabs&amp;rdquo; function on the sidebar of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have different opinions or more insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think! If you have used the textbooks I mentioned here, the Oxford textbook, or any other textbooks, you are welcomed to share and discuss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-features-of-each-textbook&#34;&gt;Main Features of Each Textbook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Publisher&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Structure&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Practice Problems&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Other Materials&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Haese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finer section division; Split in 2 books&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;More rigid, or direct&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Only trial exam papers (in the latest version) are in IB-style; Usually harder; With P3 practice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Online ebook updates automatically; Online math tools&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cambridge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Written for the old syllabus, can work for the new one but there&amp;rsquo;re things missing; Chapter summaries&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;More natural; More proofs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Many in IB-style; Usually parallel the IB difficulty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Many additional problems &amp;amp; reading materials&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-way-of-using-the-textbooks&#34;&gt;Recommended Way of Using the Textbooks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refer to the IB syllabus;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the explanations of both books together, and when they both cover a topic, look at Cambridge first;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarizing with concepts: Haese&amp;rsquo;s practice problems, Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s non-IB-style problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exam preparation: Cambridge&amp;rsquo;s IB-style problems, Haese&amp;rsquo;s trial exam papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-math-aa-hl/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note Taking</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 22:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is on my own note-taking method, which I gradually developed mainly in my 2 years in IB DP, by exploring and experimenting with a range of methods and borrowing from others. During that time, I &lt;strong&gt;refused to compromise&lt;/strong&gt; on the shortcomings in my  note-taking method as I &lt;strong&gt;continuously tried new methods&lt;/strong&gt; to arrive at my current set of note-taking methods which satisfies me for now. Together with my current note-taking method, there&amp;rsquo;re some principles of note-taking–my ultimate goal of note-taking. My current method does not achieve my purpose perfectly, but based on these principles, I can always figure out a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My note-taking method &lt;strong&gt;mainly works for the scenario in which I take notes as I listen in class and organize my notes quickly after each class.&lt;/strong&gt; I used this methods for both the arts and the sciences, although it is not equally effective for all subjects. (See the section &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;./#pros--cons-of-my-current-method&#34;&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons of My Current Method&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in this article for more details.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;preparing for exams, notes are not my main tool for revision&lt;/strong&gt;, but rather a reference source to check for gaps when I encounter a key point I don&amp;rsquo;t know; they can also be quick reminders that refresh my memory. Personally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare for many exams. For the IB DP Finals, my main tools for revision were the IB DP syllabi, past paper questions, and the textbooks that fit me the best (which I chose over two years of study), rather than my notes. I will mention that in future blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The note-taking methods I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, but didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My current note-taking principles and method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros and cons of my current method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mainly want to use this article to clearly sort out my note-taking method, and also as a reference for myself when taking notes in the future. The added purpose of this article is to hopefully provide a reference for you by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; is at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abandoned-methods&#34;&gt;Abandoned Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;copying-from-board-or-slideshow&#34;&gt;Copying from Board or Slideshow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/chem-notes.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Chemistry notes&#34; height=&#34;310px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The chemistry notes that I copied directly from the board in class and annotated after class&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method involves manually copying what a teacher writes on the board or slideshow to my notebook during class, and then using colored pens, markers and things like that to annotate or add content after class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I used it before&lt;/strong&gt;: Some teachers would write on the board in the form of notes. For example, they would list out the key points—first, second, and third, or the first, second, and third steps to solve a problem. At that point, I would think that the teacher had already organized the notes, so for convenience, I would quit organizing them myself and just copy them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;: Copying word for word can take time, and copying mechanically does not deepen my understanding of the points right on the spot.  Usually I need to spend more time at home to read and understand those copied notes, which further lowers my learning efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;annotating--highlighting&#34;&gt;Annotating &amp;amp; Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/hist-notes-1.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my History notes&#34; height=&#34;310px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My History notes made by annotating and highlighting class materials #1&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/hist-notes-2.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another page from my History notes&#34; height=&#34;310px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My History notes made by annotating and highlighting class materials #2&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is to highlight directly on the material when you already have a PPT, textbook, or similar classroom material and use the margins to annotate when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I used it before&lt;/strong&gt;: It is simple and straightforward to annotate on already existing material. When reading the brief notes, you can immediately refer to the more detailed and longer text in the course material, saving time and effort that would be used to go through multiple documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;: Insufficient blank space that is often irregular and disjointed, which makes notes more disorganized. There is little freedom and often it is not possible to add a great deal of additional content to the notes after class. Order of the notes is limited by the order in which the information appears in the materials, and it is not possible to rearrange the points according to my own logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cornell-method&#34;&gt;The Cornell Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/music-notes.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Music notes&#34; height=&#34;620px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Music notes I made with the Cornell Method&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This methods divides each note page into four sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top: Title, date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left sidebar: Keywords, subheadings, questions, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main column on the right: Body of the notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bottom: Summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I used it&lt;/strong&gt;: It seems to have an extremely high reputation on the internet and is associated with the big-name Cornell. Partitions of notes keep the content very organized. My school provides note paper with the partitions already printed out, so I can use it directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;: the partitions are not flexible enough, and this is reflected in several ways. Since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate the content of my notes in advance, when I used the paper with the dividing lines drawn on it, I often had a lot of blank space in some sections and not enough space in others. Also, the space available for the body of the notes was too small, so that I had to turn and use many pages, which would disrupt the notes. Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that the notes on each page don&amp;rsquo;t cover exactly one subsection, so not the summary section on every page will make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-totally-free-method&#34;&gt;The Totally Free Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/math-notes-1.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Math notes&#34; height=&#34;620px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The math notes I wrote with total freedom&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a method that I created myself and have tried to use. As the name suggests, it means that if I hear something in class that I don&amp;rsquo;t know, I write it down. By total freedom, I mean: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if my handwriting is messy, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if I only use abbreviations and short-hand notations, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if I draw badly or only half of the diagram, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if I scribble a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this method is: to quickly jot down &lt;strong&gt;key words&lt;/strong&gt; that can help me recall the class content. As long as I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted in class, I can definitely recall what was taught in class with a glance at my notes when I arrive home that day. With a bit of review that night, all the knowledge gets into my head. If I review the points in my notes every few days, then even if my notes look like random scribbling, in my eyes, they are already closely connected to meaningful knowledge. It no longer matters what is on the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I used it&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s free, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to spend time thinking about formatting and sentence structure when I take notes. After all, I can just scratch a few strokes and jot things down. This allows me to devote more energy into listening to the lecture, understanding it on the spot, and asking questions there, which can improve my efficiency of listening in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t use it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;: When the amount of notes increases, it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to review all my notes &amp;ldquo;every few days&amp;rdquo;. After a few weeks, when I look at my previous notes, even if I remember most of the key points, if I see a chaotic mess filled with abbreviations, it&amp;rsquo;ll take a lot of effort to understand them, which is not helpful for filling in the gaps in my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-principles&#34;&gt;My Principles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes should be easy to record in class and easy to use after class. Both are essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, my notes need to be free and &amp;ldquo;inclusive&amp;rdquo;—they need to accommodate all forms of content: words, font sizes, diagrams, formulas; they need to accommodate not only the content in class, but also any additional content that may be added after class. The format needs to look comfortable, and the structure needs to be effective in organizing the content so that it is clear and easy to access. It is important to reduce unnecessary information in the notes to avoid distractions and disruptions, but also important to have enough information that will quickly help me understand more deeply or jog my memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-method&#34;&gt;My Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/math-notes-2.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Math notes&#34; height=&#34;620px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My Math notes made with my current method&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper--notebook&#34;&gt;Paper &amp;amp; Notebook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose A4 blank paper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plastic loose leaf folder (2 holes, flipping pages from left to right)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sections&#34;&gt;Sections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start of each note entry: chapter or section number (if applicable), title (if applicable), date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left-side main column on each page: main content, including various subheadings, body of notes, important diagrams, important formulas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right-side sidebar on each page: minor points or supplementary content corresponding to the left-side content, including connections between knowledge in the main text (on the left-side) and other topics, alternative forms of formulas, less important diagrams, extensions or interesting facts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New chapters start on a separate page, otherwise I continue from where I left off with my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of having a clear dividing line on the paper, I keep a rough &amp;ldquo;fuzzy division line&amp;rdquo; in my mind, with the left and right sides allowed to be interspersed. You can think of this as a modified version of the Cornell Method&amp;rsquo;s note partitioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only take detailed notes on what I don&amp;rsquo;t know at the moment, &lt;strong&gt;refusing any urge to write down what I already know again, in the name of &amp;ldquo;consolidating knowledge &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. If I really want to write down what I have already learned, I will only write out subheadings and leave a small space for additional notes later, or for adding a few important details that might be mentioned in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use more key words and fewer complete sentences. Use symbols, abbreviations, and formatting (white space, indentation, slanted lines of text) to replace textual explanations and classify content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color: Mainly use blue and red only. Blue to take notes, red to underline key points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marking key points: Use only red straight lines as underlines for key points. No markers, curved underlines, dots, boxes, circles, bubbles, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correction: Use correction tape and correction fluid less often. For a small number of corrections, just cross out the wrong things and write the correct things next to them. For a large number of corrections, draw a box directly around the area to be corrected, cross out the entire area with a diagonal line, or simply get a new sheet of paper. To reduce corrections, I can write in pencil first for areas that I am unsure about and cover them directly with a pen when I organize the notes after class; or I can just write down the subheadings and add the content after class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annotations &amp;amp; connections: green is used in a few places to indicate other materials related to the note content, such as textbook chapters, hand-outs, etc. Sometimes it is necessary to expand on a key point in the notes, so I mark it in the body of the notes with a blue curved underline and use the same type of underline when elaborating the note on the right—the equivalent of a superscript and a footnote &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank space: Between paragraphs, there is usually enough blank space. This makes the layout looser and more comfortable for me to look at. It also makes the structure of my notes clearer and improves my efficiency in using them. The closely linked content has little space between them and I try to make it possible to see a whole part of notes at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/chn-a-notes.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Chinese A Literature notes&#34; height=&#34;620px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Another recent example: My Chinese A Literature notes made with my current method&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/note-taking/phys-notes.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A page from my Physics notes&#34; height=&#34;620px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;One more recent example: My Physics notes made with my current method&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pros--cons-of-my-current-method&#34;&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons of My Current Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose-leaf notebook, free to take out the content, change pages and add pages. Blank paper, so the format and content of notes are not restricted. Simple format, so note-taking is faster and easier, and the content is clearer, thereby improving the efficiency of getting information when using notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page edge is not aligned on the right and the pages do not turn smoothly. Pages may fall out. The iron ring in the middle of the loose-leaf binder affects the hand feeling, and when taking notes against the middle iron ring, you may poke the paper or leave fold marks, because the rings and binding device in the middle have a certain height, which makes the paper uneven under pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This note-taking method is useful for all the sciences I studied, but in the arts, it is only useful for Chinese literature—English B does not require me to take systematic notes at all, so my experience is limited; for history, I never really found any particularly systematic and effective study or note-taking method, and I usually just crammed before unit tests, midterms and finals. Only when I was preparing for the final exam ($\approx$ re-learning IB History on my own) did I feel a little more comfortable learning history 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with the drawback that the right-hand edge is not clear-cut and the pages don&amp;rsquo;t turn smoothly, I tried using a stapled notebook. This did make it easier for me to turn the pages, but I felt not only comfortable, but also constrained—I was afraid to write because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop worrying about whether I would write things wrong on a page and not be able to change for a new sheet of paper, or whether I would write things wrong on many pages at once and interrupt my notes. So far, I still prefer to use a loose-leaf notebook to take notes. For practicing problems, I think I can use a bound notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I introduced some of the note-taking methods I&amp;rsquo;ve tried. Then, I also summarized and shared my current note-taking method, with a few pages of notes taken with this method as examples. Finally, I analyzed the advantages and disadvantages of my current method. Everyone learns differently. My method works for me, but it may not work for everyone, but I hope this post has given you some inspiration for note-taking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methods I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned are &lt;strong&gt;not useless&lt;/strong&gt;. They just didn&amp;rsquo;t fit my scenario of note-taking. When I was revising for the IB DP May Exams, I printed out some Chinese A literature materials and took notes on them directly by making annotations, for example, writing answer outlines and underlining key words and phrases, which was very convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not cover the methods of organizing study materials or methods of note-taking which apply to homework, problem packets and workbooks. I will be sharing these in future articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. Although this post is mainly meant to summarize my experience for my own future reference, if you feel that my note-taking methods are not good enough, you are &lt;strong&gt;very welcomed&lt;/strong&gt; to leave a comment below to share your thoughts or email communication! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;d really like to learn more note-taking methods!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My note-taking method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Punched blank paper, loose-leaf notebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Left-side main column for body of notes, right-side sidebar is for additional content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less, less, less! Use fewer colors, fewer bubbles, boxes, stars, and use less of a variety of underlines, and so on, to mark up key points. All forms and formatting should only serve to enhance the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concise, concise, concise! Remove unnecessary information, keeping new knowledge and keywords. But still with the right amount of detail to ensure that I can understand the notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example notes: See the images in the section &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;./#my-method&#34;&gt;My Method&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like this. This allows me to explain things in depth where there&amp;rsquo;s more space, without interrupting the flow of my notes.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: Excellence or Involution?</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:09:46 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/ -&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or involution, becomes a buzzword and everyone&amp;rsquo;s source of anxiety, when we oppose &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; and turn to &lt;em&gt;tangping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, are we starting to be complacent with our status quo and even starting to deny excellence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I bumped into a post of an old classmate on WeChat Moments on this topic. I could really feel her enthusiasm for her subject of studying and her honesty with herself. That honesty is a kind of courage—the courage to recognize her own shortcomings and others&#39; excellence, the courage to stay passionate about her subject and to stay motivated despite challenges and difficulties in her studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading her post, I was so inspired to advance my own studying that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wanted to note down and share that post, so that I can remember it. So I asked that classmate for permission to post the translated version here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-translated-post&#34;&gt;The Translated Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my understanding, &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; is the meaningless effort one puts in to compete for some finite resources, but in the field of literature, being able to discover and perceive the subtleties, to think deeply, to feel with sensitivity, and to express one&amp;rsquo;s thoughts in written form are such great qualities that are worth learning from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one day, effective time management, in-depth reading, diligent writing, open-minded thinking, and rigorous essay structures will be subsumed under the infinitely expanding concept of &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;, only then I will really feel anxious and regretful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really find strange is that, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be the consensus of all those who love this discipline to take each written assignment seriously, to respect literature, to at least write out their thoughts truthfully, without any self-guilt, even if they are not interested in the topic (research direction)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very confused&amp;hellip; very confused&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/involution-post.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;220px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the original post&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;accompanying-pictures&#34;&gt;Accompanying Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the pictures that came with the classmate&amp;rsquo;s post. Each picture is followed by its translation, and the lines in quotes are those from the classmate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p1 is the trigger for this debate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/involution-1.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;The start of this debate&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger: My teaching assistant showed us two reading notes of about 10,000 characters, praising their rigorous structure and insightful expositions. However, people on my WeChat Moments are mostly worried about themselves, saying the two notes are exacerbating &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p2 and p3 are two random posts I saw on WeChat Moments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/involution-2.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;220px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Post #1&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current situation of &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; among modern university students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Before] Full marks: 100, Passing marks: 60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average students: If I get around 70 or 80 marks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be satisfied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard-working students: Strive to get 95&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neijuan&lt;/em&gt; king/queen: How can merely 100 marks satisfy me? I want to use three different methods to solve the problem, I want to answer all the additional questions, I want to get 120.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teacher: Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t even mention any additional questions, but since some people have done them, then everyone should look up to them. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a bad idea if I raise the total score to 120.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[After] Full marks: 100, Passing marks: 72&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/involution-3.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;110px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Post #2&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it hard-working or &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; to write a book review assignment, which is only worth a few tenths in a semester, which only requires 1000 words, in a way that it exceeds 10,000 words and even reaches the standard format and level of an undergraduate thesis?
Still quite confused. Today, my young little mind had a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p4 is &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/involution-4.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Definition of involution&#34; height=&#34;120px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Involution refers to the phenomenon of peers putting more effort into competing for finite resources, resulting in a decrease in each individual&amp;rsquo;s effort-to-reward ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-reflection&#34;&gt;My Reflection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ask myself for my most honest answer, I know I&amp;rsquo;m an ordinary person. Although, now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be satisfied with mediocrity, if anything unpredictable happens in the future and leaves me with no other choice, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like such an unimaginably terrible idea. But if one day, I only scoffed at the outstanding abilities and wonderful characters of others and always labeled them as &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; or even mocked them, that would just be my pathetic self-deception. &lt;strong&gt;I hope that I can confidently pursue my own excellence, and more importantly, I hope that I will retain the ability to appreciate other&amp;rsquo;s excellence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese for &amp;ldquo;involution&amp;rdquo;, a little-known academic term. In the Chinese context, it describes an environment of endless competitions which require an enormous input that is disproportionate to the limited outcome. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.oxchina.net/seminar-introduction-involution/&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It literally translates to &amp;ldquo;lying flat&amp;rdquo;. In the Chinese context, the term extends its meaning to a state of avoiding competitions and being complacent to reduce anxiety. A pessimistic response to &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; which recently became popular on the Chinese internet.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 