<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:09:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Excellence or Involution?</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:09:46 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/ -&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or involution, becomes a buzzword and everyone&amp;rsquo;s source of anxiety, when we oppose &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; and turn to &lt;em&gt;tangping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, are we starting to be complacent with our status quo and even starting to deny excellence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I bumped into a post of an old classmate on WeChat Moments on this topic. I could really feel her enthusiasm for her subject of studying and her honesty with herself. That honesty is a kind of courage—the courage to recognize her own shortcomings and others&#39; excellence, the courage to stay passionate about her subject and to stay motivated despite challenges and difficulties in her studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading her post, I was so inspired to advance my own studying that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wanted to note down and share that post, so that I can remember it. So I asked that classmate for permission to post the translated version here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-translated-post&#34;&gt;The Translated Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my understanding, &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; is the meaningless effort one puts in to compete for some finite resources, but in the field of literature, being able to discover and perceive the subtleties, to think deeply, to feel with sensitivity, and to express one&amp;rsquo;s thoughts in written form are such great qualities that are worth learning from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one day, effective time management, in-depth reading, diligent writing, open-minded thinking, and rigorous essay structures will be subsumed under the infinitely expanding concept of &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;, then I will really feel anxious and regretful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really find strange is that, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be the consensus of all those who love this discipline to take each written assignment seriously, to respect literature, to at least write out their thoughts truthfully, without any self-guilt, even if they are not interested in the topic (research direction)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very confused&amp;hellip; very confused&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/involution-post.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;220px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the original post&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;accompanying-pictures&#34;&gt;Accompanying Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the pictures that came with the classmate&amp;rsquo;s post. Each picture is followed by its translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p1 is the trigger for this debate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/involution-1.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;The start of this debate&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger: My teaching assistant showed us two reading notes of about 10,000 words, praising their rigorous structure and insightful expositions. However, people on my WeChat Moments are mostly worried about themselves, saying the two notes are exacerbating &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p2 and p3 are two random posts I saw on WeChat Moments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/involution-2.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;A post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;220px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Post #1&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current situation of &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; among modern university students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Before] Full marks: 100, Passing marks: 60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average students: If I get around 70 or 80 marks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be satisfied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard-working students: Strive to get 95&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neijuan&lt;/em&gt; king/queen: How can merely 100 marks satisfy me? I want to use three different methods to solve the problem, I want to answer all the additional questions, I want to get 120.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teacher: Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t even mention any additional questions, but since some people have done them, then everyone should look up to them. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a bad idea if I raise the total score to 120.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[After] Full marks: 100, Passing marks: 72&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/involution-3.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Another post from WeChat Moments&#34; height=&#34;110px&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Post #2&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it hard-working or &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; to write a book review assignment, which is only worth a few tenths in a semester, which only requires 1000 words, in a way that it exceeds 10,000 words and even reaches the standard format and level of an undergraduate thesis?
Still quite confused. Today, my young little mind had a shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p4 is &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/involution-4.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Definition of involution&#34; height=&#34;120px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Involution refers to the phenomenon of peers putting more effort into competing for finite resources, resulting in a decrease in each individual&amp;rsquo;s effort-to-reward ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-reflection&#34;&gt;My Reflection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ask myself for my most honest answer, I know I&amp;rsquo;m an ordinary person. Although, now, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be satisfied with mediocrity, if anything unpredictable happens in the future and leaves me with no other choice, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like such an unimaginably terrible idea. But if one day, I only scoffed at the outstanding abilities and wonderful characters of others and always labeled them as &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; or even mocked them, that would just be my pathetic self-deception. &lt;strong&gt;I hope that I can confidently pursue my own excellence, and more importantly, I hope that I will retain the ability to appreciate other&amp;rsquo;s excellence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese for &amp;ldquo;involution&amp;rdquo;, a little-known academic term. In the Chinese context, it describes an environment of endless competitions which require an enormous input that is disproportionate to the limited outcome. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.oxchina.net/seminar-introduction-involution/&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It literally translates to &amp;ldquo;lying flat&amp;rdquo;. In the Chinese context, the term extends its meaning to a state of avoiding competitions and being complacent to reduce anxiety. A pessimistic response to &lt;em&gt;neijuan&lt;/em&gt; which recently became popular on the Chinese internet.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>My Tips &amp; Experience with IB Textbooks: Physics HL</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-physics-hl/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 21:25:13 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-physics-hl/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-physics-hl/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in my blog series called &amp;ldquo;My Tips &amp;amp; Experience with IB Textbooks&amp;rdquo;. The IB subjects covered in this series are DP Physics, Math AA, Chemistry, History, and Chinese A Lit. The corresponding levels and syllabus versions (year of first assessment) are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Subject&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Level&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Other Posts in this Series&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Physics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This article&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Math AA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To be updated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chemistry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To be updated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;History&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To be updated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chinese A Lit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To be updated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are the IB DP subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve studied. I&amp;rsquo;ve used at least 2 textbooks (or study guides) for each of these subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the &lt;strong&gt;Physics&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks that I&amp;rsquo;ve used. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the textbooks by their publishers, compare and contrast their features, their strengths and weaknesses (in my opinion), and finally give my thoughts on how to use textbooks. All the information here is for reference only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL; DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-features-of-each-textbook&#34;&gt;Main features of Each Textbook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Publisher&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanations &amp;amp; Derivations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Practice Problems&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Structure &amp;amp; Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pearson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Only a few extensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Includes IB past paper problems that aren&amp;rsquo;t indicated as such&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tight formatting; With content outside of IB syllabus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oxford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A lot of extensions, Many complete derivations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Includes IB past paper problems that are indicated as such; No exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Covers IB syllabus perfectly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cambridge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Some extensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A large number of original questions, A full range of question types&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;With content outside of IB syllabus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-way-of-using-textbooks&#34;&gt;Recommended Way of Using Textbooks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main textbook：Choose 1 between Oxford &amp;amp; Cambridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting textbook：The other textbook (Oxford or Cambridge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional material：Pearson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbook-reviews&#34;&gt;Textbook Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most important things about physics textbooks are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good explanations&lt;/strong&gt;: Clear, natural, and ingenious introductions and explanations of physical phenomena and theoretical derivations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good practice problems&lt;/strong&gt;: The problems test not only the ability to apply knowledge, but also the understanding of knowledge. The question style should be similar to those in IB past papers, but the content of the questions should be novel and varied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my points will be centered around these two ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my two years of DP, I used 3 books from 3 publishers in total:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pearson-education&#34;&gt;Pearson Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/pearson-physics-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Higher Level Physics, published by Pearson&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Higher Level Physics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2nd Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Chris Hamper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN：978-1-447-95902-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impression I got from this book was that &lt;strong&gt;there was a lot of content and the pages were almost full&lt;/strong&gt;. Every time I saw it, I was a little more reassured—the book talks about so many things, so there must be enough for me to use in exams, right? But the more I used it, the more I thought that sometimes, the book had too much and it was too full. In my opinion, textbooks need to have just the right amount of detail, and they also need to be concise and clear so that they can convey information to the reader efficiently. But if you have enough time to read, it isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad idea to use this book as an interesting reading material to expand your knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiments &amp;amp; Formula Derivations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experimental investigation sections of this book contain some instructions and guidance for experiments, but the more detailed &lt;strong&gt;lab worksheets&lt;/strong&gt; are in the e-book, which does not seem to come with the paper copy. If you use this book for self-study, that&#39; going to be a challenge. But if you are using this book while following your school, then you should be able to ask your teacher for the lab instructions. The book&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pearson.com/uk/hotlinks/products/9781447959021.html&#34;&gt;online resources&lt;/a&gt; also mainly focus on  experiments. There&amp;rsquo;re links to many &lt;strong&gt;experimental simulations&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can save yourself the trouble of googling for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;formula derivations&lt;/strong&gt; are very helpful. The one that I remember the most clearly is the derivation of $v=\pm\omega\sqrt{x_0^2-x^2}$ for simple harmonic motion. In the derivation, the book squares $x=x_0\sin\omega t$ and $v=\omega x_0\cos\omega t$ respectively, so you can derive the formula naturally using the trigonometric identity $\sin^2x+\cos^2x=1$. For the Doppler effect, the book also has a fairly clear &lt;strong&gt;diagram&lt;/strong&gt; which helps the reader understand quickly when combined with the book&amp;rsquo;s algebraic derivation. That is especially helpful in the situation of a stationary source and a moving observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each section of the book is followed by a set of &lt;strong&gt;exercise&lt;/strong&gt; for that section, and at the end of each chapter, there is also a set of &lt;strong&gt;IB exam-style questions&lt;/strong&gt;. However, some of the questions are from &lt;strong&gt;IB past papers&lt;/strong&gt; and the book does not indicate that, so if you do a lot of IB past paper questions, when using this book, you might waste some time doing the ones you&amp;rsquo;ve already done before. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily bad to re-do some questions though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is specifically for &lt;strong&gt;HL&lt;/strong&gt;, so there isn&amp;rsquo;t a strong sense of division between each topic. For example, Topic 5 Waves and Topic 9 Wave Phenomena are combined in the same chapter. However, depending on the class setup at your school, your teacher might cover SL content first, and then do the HL content separately. Then there isn&amp;rsquo;t really a point for the book to combine the related topics into one chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that &lt;strong&gt;not all chapters in the book correspond to the Topics&lt;/strong&gt; in the IB syllabus. So if you read the book on your own and try to follow the pace of your class, this structure might make it harder for you to tell what content is SL, what content is HL, and what content in the book is under which Topic. Unlike this one, the two other physics textbooks that I&amp;rsquo;ll mention below separate SL and HL content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;oxford-university-press&#34;&gt;Oxford University Press&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/oxford-physics-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Physics: Course Companion, published by Oxford&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Physics: Course Companion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 2014 Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: David Homer, Michael Bowen-Jones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-0-19-839213-2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about this book is that it’s &amp;ldquo;hand-picked&amp;rdquo; by the IB-it‘s the only textbook that was &lt;strong&gt;jointly developed by the IB and the publisher&lt;/strong&gt;. So it reflects some of the IB&amp;rsquo;s inside information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is clear in the fact that this book covers the IB syllabus exactly. For example, the Pearson textbook includes color forces in the chapter on Topic 7 &amp;amp; 11 Modern Physics, and the Cambridge textbook includes the formula for thermal conduction in the chapter on Topic 8 Energy Production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiments &amp;amp; Formula Derivations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many detailed &lt;strong&gt;experimental investigation sections&lt;/strong&gt; in this book, and often the experiments are used to introduce or verify theories, allowing the reader to develop an intuition for physical phenomena and to understand abstract formulas more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, this book&amp;rsquo;s content on capacitance is introduced through an experiment which links capacitance to two familiar concepts—electric field and potential, so that reader can quickly become familiar with the new concept of &amp;ldquo;capacitance&amp;rdquo;. In contrast, the Cambridge textbook is a bit less organic in its introduction of capacitance. Of course, fundamentally, I think this problem is because the IB Physics doesn&amp;rsquo;t do Gauß&amp;rsquo;s Law, so the textbooks have to either introduce capacitance in a roundabout way or in a sketchy way to avoid going too far beyond the syllabus😕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;formula derivations&lt;/strong&gt; in the book are also very detailed and easy to understand. Also, there&amp;rsquo;re appropriate &lt;strong&gt;expansions&lt;/strong&gt;, which greatly aid understanding. The most memorable part was the derivation of $\bar E_k = \frac{3}{2}k_BT$ for ideal gases in the chapter on Topic 3 Thermal Physics. The steps are clear and explained in detail (e.g. where the &amp;ldquo;3&amp;rdquo; in the above equation comes from). The Cambridge text skips the derivation of how the &amp;ldquo;3&amp;rdquo; came to be, while the Pearson text doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the derivation at all and states the formula directly as a fact. It was exactly because I had seen this derivation, I remembered that the kinetic energy in the equation is the average kinetic energy, averaged over each gas molecule. That directly helped me to get a question right in a mock exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the Cambridge and Pearson books are sometimes a little less friendly to students who don&amp;rsquo;t like or aren&amp;rsquo;t good at memorization, or those who want some extensions. In that case, the Oxford textbook is relatively better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;re worked examples that come with every average textbook, but there&amp;rsquo;re &lt;strong&gt;no informal exercises&lt;/strong&gt; to help the reader get familiar with new concepts. When it comes to that, this book is not as good as the Pearson and Cambridge books. This book does have &lt;strong&gt;IB exam-style questions&lt;/strong&gt; though, at the end of each chapter. There&amp;rsquo;re some original questions, but there are still a lot of questions from &lt;strong&gt;IB past papers&lt;/strong&gt;, which are indicated in the book. So if you do a lot of IB past paper questions, you might not get many new questions from this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of this book, there is a line saying you can find more exercises on the Oxford University Press &lt;a href=&#34;www.oxfordsecondary.co.uk/ib-physics&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, but I only found the &lt;a href=&#34;https://global.oup.com/education/secondary/curricula/ib-diploma/science/phsyicsanswers/?region=international&#34;&gt;answers&lt;/a&gt; to the practice problems already in this textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, personally, I think this book is a bit weak on practice problems. But my physics teacher said this book has good problems. I think he meant that this book &lt;strong&gt;is very good at picking good questions&lt;/strong&gt; from IB past papers. I agree with this, and I trust his judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HL content and SL content are &lt;strong&gt;separated&lt;/strong&gt;, so you might feel some gaps between the related chapters across SL and HL, but each chapter corresponds exactly to each Topic of the IB syllabus, which is more convenient for the reader to search for information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layout is &lt;strong&gt;looser&lt;/strong&gt; than Pearson&amp;rsquo;s. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising (in a good way) to see that in Topic 9 Fields, the contents on electric and gravitational fields are &lt;strong&gt;color-coded&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a clever way to make everything clear. It&amp;rsquo;s especially helpful when comparing the two fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cambridge-university-press&#34;&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//jiaxcuit.github.io/images/cambridge-physics-tb.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Cover of Physics for the IB Diploma Coursebook, published by Cambridge&#34; height=&#34;350px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: &lt;em&gt;Physics for the IB Diploma Coursebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edition: 6th Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: K. A. Tsokos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 978-1-107-62819-9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My overall impression of this book is that it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;detailed enough&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;concise enough&lt;/strong&gt;. So there is not much to complain about. Some content in the book is outside of the IB syllabus, but that&amp;rsquo;s not really a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formula Derivations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the style of this book&amp;rsquo;s formula derivation is similar to that of the Oxford textbook in that they are &lt;strong&gt;not &amp;ldquo;afraid&amp;rdquo; of giving extensions&lt;/strong&gt;, and they go beyond the syllabus in a way that is helpful for the reader. An example is the derivation of the decay formula in Topic 11 Modern Physics. Both books start from $-\frac{\mathrm{d} N}{\mathrm{d} t}=\lambda N$ and use calculus to derive $N=N_0e^{-\lambda t}$. Their derivations deepen the reader&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the fact that the decay rate is proportional to the number of undecayed nuclei. The Pearson textbook doesn&amp;rsquo;t have this derivation. In fact, the Pearson textbook has fewer extensions in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compared to the Oxford textbook, this book expands slightly less on the syllabus content. I&amp;rsquo;ve already mentioned $\bar E_k = \frac{3}{2}k_BT$ in the previous sections of this blog post, so here&amp;rsquo;s another example: the derivation of the fact that the electric field strength inside a charged metal sphere is zero. This book states as a fact that inside the sphere, the electric potential is constant, i.e. the electric field strength is zero, while the Oxford textbook proves this point with mathematical tools. As you can see, the Oxford textbook expands on the content a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice Problems &amp;amp; Additional Materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this book&amp;rsquo;s practice problems and additional materials &lt;strong&gt;the best among these three physics textbooks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has &lt;strong&gt;sufficient exercises&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of each section of each chapter. Those are not only questions that examine the application of knowledge (i.e. normal questions like in exams), but also questions leading the reader to further thinking and discussion. An example is Exercise 30 for Topic 11.3 Capacitance. It asks the reader draw a graph of the potential difference across a parallel plate capacitor ($V$) against the charge on a single plate ($q$), leading the reader to consider the meaning of the area under the curve. This deepens the reader&amp;rsquo;s understanding of $E=\frac{1}{2}CV^2=\frac{1}{2}Vq=\frac{1}{2}\frac{q^2}{C}$, the formula for the energy stored in a parallel plate capacitor. This exercise also tests the reader&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the concept that the capacitance of a parallel plate capacitor doesn&amp;rsquo;t vary with voltage or charge. This is much more helpful than only looking at the equations $E=\frac{1}{2}CV^2$ and $C=\frac{q}{V}$ in the &lt;em&gt;Data Booklet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also &lt;strong&gt;comprehensive practice problems in the style of IB exam questions&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of each chapter. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if all the questions are original, but I never found any original IB past paper questions when I was working with the book. There are both multiple choice questions and free response questions that are a bit longer. Compared to the Pearson and Oxford textbook problems, this book&amp;rsquo;s content is &lt;strong&gt;richer and more varied&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find &lt;strong&gt;more practice problems and answers&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/go/&#34;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt; of Cambridge University Press for free. By registering with your email, you can search, browse, and download resources from the Cambridge online system. All those questions are additional to the exercises in this book, so there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no need to worry about running out of problems to do. Note that at the end of the book, there&amp;rsquo;re only answers for the exercises, while the answers for the exam-style questions at the end of each chapter are on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HL and SL chapters are &lt;strong&gt;separated&lt;/strong&gt;, so related chapters across Sl and HL have small gaps in between. But each chapter corresponds exactly to the IB syllabus Topics. The layout is similar to that of the Oxford textbook, both being &lt;strong&gt;looser&lt;/strong&gt; than the Pearson text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book has one small, almost insignificant drawback: it combines the two requirements in the IB syllabus, Comprehension and Application, when it lists out the learning objectives at the beginning of each section. The Pearson and Oxford books, on the other hand, both list the Comprehension and Application requirements separately, which is a bit clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-textbooks&#34;&gt;Using Textbooks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the analysis above, I think the best approach is to choose &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; between the Oxford and Cambridge textbooks as the main textbook. That means, you read the relevant chapter in that book immediately after each lesson at school, while the other book is used less often. If you choose the Cambridge textbook as your main textbook, then when you don&amp;rsquo;t understand something in that book, you can read the corresponding chapter in the Oxford textbook, and vice versa. I think the Pearson textbook can be an additional option. It can be a reference source when you don&amp;rsquo;t understand the explanations in both the Oxford and Cambridge textbooks, or when there is a disagreement between the two books, or as a place to find practice problems. (Of course, if your school uses a textbook in teaching, you can simply follow your school&amp;rsquo;s plan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, each textbook explains knowledge differently—sometimes in a different way, sometimes with a different focus—so, actually, I think &lt;strong&gt;we should look at all the textbooks and synthesize their information&lt;/strong&gt; when studying. However, our time is limited, so we can&amp;rsquo;t read everything in the textbooks—we have to give up on reading some of the things. But if we know we have some weaker areas in terms of understanding, it&amp;rsquo;s better to read all the relevant contents in all three textbooks, follow their explanations carefully, think about them and understand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled a bit with the Doppler effect, but after reading the three different explanations in the three textbooks, I got a better grasp of it. The additional option, the Pearson textbook, was even more helpful than the other two. Everyone says you need to widen your reading for the humanities, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the same for the sciences. Read more and think more, there is always an explanation that suits you😆&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I think people need to know, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that not all chapters in a textbook give the explanations that suit you. For example, I personally like the Oxford textbook&amp;rsquo;s explanation in Topic 11.3 Capacitance, but I think the Cambridge textbook&amp;rsquo;s explanation in Topic 10 Fields suited me better than that in the Oxford textbook. So my suggestion is to be flexible when using the textbooks. If you just can&amp;rsquo;t really understand a part in a book, don&amp;rsquo;t  rush to think that you didn&amp;rsquo;t learn things well! Always try using another textbook!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thing, I think that although textbooks are only tools and you don&amp;rsquo;t need to read them word by word from beginning to end, you &lt;strong&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t just skim over them&lt;/strong&gt; either. After you skim through to find the chapter or paragraph you need to study, you should probably slow down to read and understand it carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I talked about three &lt;strong&gt;Physics&lt;/strong&gt; textbooks for the 2016 IB syllabus. The books are published by Pearson, Oxford, and Cambridge respectively. I listed out their &lt;strong&gt;features&lt;/strong&gt;, compared and contrasted the &lt;strong&gt;strengths and weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt; of each of them in my mind. Throughout the process, I tried to reference to concrete examples. At the end, based on my own learning experience, I gave some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions&lt;/strong&gt; for using textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still updating this series of blog posts, and I&amp;rsquo;ll post links to the new updates in the table at the beginning of this blog post. Feel free to check them out if you&amp;rsquo;re interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover any specific physics study methods, such as how to do problems effectively, nor does it cover specific tips for studying IB physics, such as exam skills. All of these I will mention in future blog posts. For more posts on physics, please use the &amp;ldquo;tabs&amp;rdquo; function on the sidebar of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have different opinions or more insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-physics-hl/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 23:06:41 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/about/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/about/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;Notice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is under construction and testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to set up a Chinese-English bilingual blog, but apparently it&amp;rsquo;s quite hard. So as you navigate through the blog, although I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to translate stuff into English to reach a wider audience, there might still be things that are only available in Chinese. &lt;em&gt;(Feel free to be proud if you know Chinese, my fella!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates will come soon! (Hopefully after I learn more HTML and CSS.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;博客正在测试中，会在近期尽快更新XD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我正在摸索着建立一个中英双语的博客，但实在是挺难的。所以你猛地一看，有很多内容都是英文的，因为我想让博客受众更广，所以只能用这个权宜之计。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但不用担心，所有内容都有中文版！有两种方法可以改成中文：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;简单的方式：点击左侧边栏中的“中文”和“归档”，这样就可以看到中文博文啦。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;稍微复杂一点：只要把链接中的“en”改成“zh”，就可以直接看到对应的中文页面啦！举例如下：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;把
https://jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/
改成
https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/uni-app/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;blog-content&#34;&gt;Blog Content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! This is a pretty chill personal blog, mainly sharing my own IB &lt;strong&gt;study experience&lt;/strong&gt; and my &lt;strong&gt;study resources&lt;/strong&gt;, but also sharing bits and pieces from my life. To see the posts, please use the &amp;ldquo;Tags&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Archive&amp;rdquo; functions in the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-do-i-blog&#34;&gt;Why do I blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IB, a not-so-popular education system, has an &lt;strong&gt;amazing transparency&lt;/strong&gt;. There are very few study resources available online, and there are even fewer places to learn from others&#39; studying experiences. After all the troubles I had in the IB, I was so pissed that I decided to carry on with the spirit of CAS and share as much information as I could. &lt;strong&gt;Hopefully, I can help every single one of you who is suffering in the IB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an answer from Zhihu&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that resonates with me a lot: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/439087609/answer/1675869050&#34;&gt;What do you think you really learned from IB? - Andy Prime&amp;rsquo;s answer - Zhihu&lt;/a&gt;. Come on, you can do this! You&amp;rsquo;re not alone in the IB. And IB is &lt;strong&gt;not that useless&lt;/strong&gt; after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-ib-experience&#34;&gt;My IB Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I share on my blog can be influenced by many factors such as subject choices, syllabus versions, grades, my personal learning style, etc. I kindly ask you to keep these in mind. I hope I won&amp;rsquo;t mislead people in areas I&amp;rsquo;m not good at😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session: M21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HL: Math A&amp;amp;A, Physics, English B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SL: Chemistry, History, Chinese A: Literature (Self-Taught)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EE: Physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicted Grades: 41+3. I got my only 6 in History. My TOK was predicted a B, and my EE was predicted an A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of COVID, I &lt;strong&gt;did not study any Option units&lt;/strong&gt;, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience or advice regarding them. However, I have skimmed through the Astrophysics and Engineering Physics Options, so I&amp;rsquo;m not completely unfamiliar with those ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum of &lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt; is very flexible. We have chosen these topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Case Studies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Prescribed subject 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Move to Global War&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan, Germany, Italy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Topic 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Causes and Effects of 20th Century Wars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;World War One, Chinese Civil War(s), Spanish Civil War&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Topic 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Authoritarian States (20th Century)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany, Italy, China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the arts and the sciences in the IB, I seem to be better at the sciences. Comparing essay writing and solving exam problems, I seem to be better at solving problems. However, although I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly good at writing essays, it seems like physics lab reports are not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-i-am-&#34;&gt;So, I am &amp;hellip;?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can probably give myself a bunch of labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a procrastinator who always struggles with deadlines (but still manages to meet them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also a perfectionist who likes to get my working area well-organized before I start studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also passionate about methodologies: studying methods, organization methods, time management, etc. I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn all kinds of things from all kinds of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe great tools can boost efficiency, and good thinking and studying methods are more important than blind diligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I can be outgoing in front of my friends, I&amp;rsquo;m rather introverted when facing strangers, so please contact me via email first: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jiaxcuit@gmail.com&#34;&gt;jiaxcuit@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Comments and email communication are always welcomed! (Remember to log in with Github to post comments.) Thanks🤗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is in Chinese.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/about/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: Mother Tongue</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:58:34 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/ -&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was on a team with some students from my school for an online math competition. One of the students on the team (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Student-A) who was from another grade had a Chinese name, so I assumed that she was Chinese or ethnically Chinese. When we met at school, I was &amp;ldquo;relieved&amp;rdquo; to come up and suggest, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk in Chinese!&amp;rdquo; But of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t go well in the reality. Having heard my words, Student-A smiled awkwardly and said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at Chinese.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, Student-A spoke Chinese with me that day. We also spoke Chinese during the preparation right before the competition, when it was just the two of us talking. Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there was anything wrong with her Chinese—I was even a little surprised that she knew the Chinese word for a math terminology like calculus. So, I speculated as I apologized for my rudeness in my mind: Is she so used to hearing people say she is not good at Chinese that she is not confident in herself? I thought she was excellent and she probably knew a lot of Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, when other team members were there, we just talked in English. After the competition, when only the two of us talked together, we also used English. I have to say, shamefully, that when talking about topics related to our school and school work, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a little less stumbling if I use English. I also tried to find excuses for myself: If I talked to with Student-A in English, she would actually be more comfortable, right? We didn&amp;rsquo;t really know each other before, so I should&amp;rsquo;ve been more considerate of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, but—I do understand English, yet English is not &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in an international school for a few years now, and I have never forgotten my mother tongue. I feel proud and lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud that I have been listening and reading in my mother tongue. I am proud that I have been working hard to learn IB Chinese literature. I am proud that I have been writing in my native language even outside of class (not at a particularly great level though😅). Because of all these things, I could see a wider world and convey my thoughts to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky that my family did not make me leave my native language environment in grade 7, grade 8, or even in primary, so I could be immersed in an environment where teaching and instructions are in Chinese for a few more years. However, some of my friends left home early, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if they continued to learn their mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to criticize anyone, let alone despise anyone&lt;/strong&gt;. There are so many reasons for leaving a native language environment, and many of the reasons involve things that are simply out of personal control. Actually, I admire my friends who left home early, became independent quickly, and gradually adapted to their new environments. Moreover, I truly aspire to their excellence and mental strength. Based on my own experience, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to leave a native language environment and adapt to a new one. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the same for them. After all, a person&amp;rsquo;s mother tongue is closely related to his/her identity and culture, which are probably deeply rooted in everyone&amp;rsquo;s heart. Not everyone is the same as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/04/01/andrew-yang-coronavirus-discrimination/&#34;&gt;some ridiculous politicians&lt;/a&gt; who are ashamed of their identity all day long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might sound condescending, but I still feel deeply sorry for those who have consciously or accidentally forgotten their native language, or those whose mother tongue skills have largely declined. Like many people, I was once lost and confused. I once thought, &amp;ldquo;How wonderful it would be if my mother tongue was English?&amp;rdquo; And I wanted to learn English to a native level. But what about Chinese&amp;hellip;? I thought at the time, it probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore. However, I slowly, slowly realized that knowing Chinese is really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized this because of one of my teachers. Once, she happened to learn that I read Chinese textbooks in addition to English textbooks. Unexpectedly, she immediately yelled out with great excitement, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s fantastic! I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that you could read academic materials in Chinese! That&amp;rsquo;s really, really great.&amp;rdquo; It was only then that I realized reading academic materials in Chinese was a skill. It was so late for me to realize. I had always benefited from knowing Chinese, but had never recognized its importance. But why was my teacher so excited? I recalled that she had mentioned she knew Cantonese, but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t good at it. Again, please pardon my rude speculations—would it be possible, that she had some regrets, or perhaps some late realizations, so she didn&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to compliment me in such a generous way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also realized something more. When I read the delicate and thoughtful literature works in my IB Chinese literature class, when I feel the subtleties in the tiny details of the texts, when I write down what I see, hear and feel in Chinese freely, I start to feel something much more precious than the practical value of the Chinese language—Chinese has allowed me to enjoy the beauty of language and literature with the most genuine emotional experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of mother tongues, I remember a classmate I met in my German language class, Classmate-B. Classmate-B is a dual citizen of the US and Germany. She said that her father was German, but her father never taught her German, and she didn&amp;rsquo;t know why. Having grown up in the US, Classmate-B naturally speaks English on a daily basis. English should have been enough for her, because after all, it is the world language. But she still came to Germany and stayed with her German-speaking uncle to learn German. She wanted to apply for a German university after she leaves school, because universities in Germany are free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German could have been a mother tongue for Classmate-B, and she could have learned it naturally, little by little, as she grew up. But now, she needs to put in the extra effort to learn it. I guess, German would still be a foreign language for her, instead of &lt;strong&gt;her&lt;/strong&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask me: what are the benefits of learning your mother tongue? I think, even in the most utilitarian sense, it would avoid troubles such as Classmate-B&amp;rsquo;s. Not to mention the spiritual wealth that comes from mastering your mother tongue, which is truly priceless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese is my mother tongue, &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; language. In an international environment, I am still able to use my mother tongue. I am proud of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is not &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; anymore😂 But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start a new series for now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t bother coming up with a name for a new series, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it as it is. There are lots of thoughts, but my honest thoughts. Thank you for reading this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &amp;ldquo;a language that I understand&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;my language&amp;rdquo; many times in the article. That was inspired by a poster in a German classroom at our school. The original (mis)quote&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on the poster was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you talk to a man in a language he understands, that goes to his head. If you talk to him in his language, that goes to his heart.
—Nelson Mandela&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.harvard.edu/pierredegalbert/node/632263&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by researcher Pierre de Galbert to learn some interesting background stories behind the quote.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Friends</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 04:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/ -&lt;p&gt;I will be posting links to some of my friends&#39; blogs here from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s really a nice coincidence that we are meeting each other on the internet. Since you are already here, you might as well check out these blogs too😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ib-land.netlify.app&#34;&gt;IB Land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my friend Violet&amp;rsquo;s blog in English, mainly sharing her IB learning experience and study methods. She&amp;rsquo;s really great! And she really has a lot of experience in IB because she went through IB PYP, MYP and DP. That&amp;rsquo;s the whole of IB system.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Focus, Habit, Feedback: 3 Tips for Exam Prep</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:17:59 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-to-share&#34;&gt;Video to Share&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the IB exams are approaching, I started to look for a study method more suitable for short term preparation. Just at the same time, Coach_K updated a video on Bilibili about this exact topic. I watched it and thought he indeed had a point, and the video was a great reminder for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1oZ4y1w76F?share_source=copy_web&#34;&gt;CK - How Should You Prepare for Exams? The Powerful Method of a Student Who Scored Nearly Full Marks in SAT&lt;/a&gt; (【CK】如何备考？高考近满分学霸的高能方法). The video lasts for 8 min 50 s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K is really excellent and he&amp;rsquo;s a treasure-like uploader whom I&amp;rsquo;ve been following for a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about him again when I share time management methods and more study methods in the future. If you are interested, you can check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://space.bilibili.com/474571157/video&#34;&gt;Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s other videos&lt;/a&gt; on Bilibili&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;key-points&#34;&gt;Key Points&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K brings up 3 points in the video: &lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Habit&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;, in the order of increasing importance. He points out that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on your task allows us to accomplish more in a short period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Habits allow us to save energy by reducing the number of unnecessary decisions we need to make and reducing the effort we put into making those decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback allows us to check for and fill in the gaps in our knowledge. It also allows us to improve our strategy and tactics for doing practice problems, so that we can make the most out of each problem we do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking about &amp;ldquo;feedback&amp;rdquo;, Coach_K emphasized the importance of &lt;strong&gt;reflection&lt;/strong&gt;. Reflection means looking back at a problem that we did wrong, finding the reason why we made the mistake, suggesting a solution to the situation, and starting to improve based on the solution right away. As he said, reflection is indeed a painful process, but if we just do problems without analyzing why we make mistakes and without improving specifically in our weaker areas, we are just creating an illusion that we are trying, which is a waste of our time and energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s point about habits was something I had never realized. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At school, when I follow a set schedule and have a teacher leading my revision, I get clear instructions, so I everything&amp;rsquo;s clear and I can revise without worrying much. At home, when I have to plan my daily revision, I get annoyed a lot by numerous small things: what paper I should do today, when I should do it, how long I should spend on it, and even smaller things such as what to eat for lunch and when to wash up. All of these trivial things require me to invest my energy to make decisions, reducing the amount of energy I have for exam preparation. These tedious and trivial tasks would affect me much less if I could &amp;ldquo;mindlessly&amp;rdquo; follow a schedule to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The similarity between Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s video and my previous thinking is that &amp;lsquo;reflection&amp;rsquo; is painful but necessary. After listening to his summary, my own thoughts also became clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current history teacher never goes over our tests or exams with us in class. He lets us look at his written feedback and annotations on the papers on our own, and if we have questions, he asks us to approach him individually and talk to him one-on-one. This form of teaching gave us a lot of freedom, but because of this, I often did the papers, got them graded, put them aside, and never touched them again. Practically, I could always go back to review the exam papers. It didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter when I do that. So I allocated my limited time to more important and more urgent tasks in other subjects. Psychologically, I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t dare to look at my own mistakes. Reviewing one&amp;rsquo;s own exam papers is indeed painful and must take a lot of effort. But when I actually picked up my exam papers and reviewed them word by word, and when I compared my answer with the model answer to see why exactly I lost marks, I did learn a lot and made huge progress. In my previous study process, I always skipped the reflection step. That&amp;rsquo;s why I got stuck with my grade in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I summarized the three tips for exam preparation in Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s video on Bilibili, which are focus, habit, and feedback. Then, I briefly cleared up my thoughts with reference to my own learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post only mentions that reflection is painful, but in fact, I know that not only is reflection painful, but learning (or any work you do that gives actual output) is also painful. Or, to be more precise, it is &lt;strong&gt;energy consuming&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing more resources on learning methods on this blog later, and I&amp;rsquo;ll expand on this point as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video is in Chinese.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His videos are in Chinese, and the video platform Bilibili is also in Chinese (except for the Investor Relations section😂).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Assumptions for an Ideal Transformer</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 12:10:42 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/ -&lt;p&gt;Transformers are closely related to induction in the study of electricity and magnetism. Here, I share an article&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/T0DcwTlz0DYTKsijbmVpBA&#34;&gt;Weekly Three Questions - Grade 12: (170) What is &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; for an ideal transformer?&lt;/a&gt; (【每周三题】高三【170】理想变压器都“理想”了什么？), by Wu Aixiong (吴爱兄). This article has largely deepened my understanding of transformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is from &lt;strong&gt;Physics Learning Research&lt;/strong&gt; (物理学习研究), a WeChat Official Account. It posts many other similar articles on physics that investigate into individual topics, including example problems, explanations, and exercises to consolidate knowledge. Most of the content is high quality and is suitable for students from grade 9 to grade 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explains the &lt;strong&gt;components&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;theoretical principles&lt;/strong&gt; of a transformer, and then explains the &lt;strong&gt;assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; of an ideal transformer. The article also discusses in detail the various &lt;strong&gt;conclusions&lt;/strong&gt; regarding transformers, such as the conditions for $\frac{\epsilon_1}{\epsilon_2} = \frac{V_1}{V_2}$ to be true. The article covers topics such as &lt;strong&gt;inductive reactance&lt;/strong&gt; which is not covered in IB physics, but it is mentioned less frequently in the article and only appears at the very end. The four exercises in the article are helpful as they closely relate to the content in IB Physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that due to formatting issues, the first part of question (1) is centered below the first picture, however it is not a caption of the picture, so be careful not to think it is the caption or miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, you are welcome to share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article is in Chinese.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chinese A Lit: P1 Skills &amp; Exemplars</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 15:05:52 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/&#34;&gt;中文文学 P1 写作方法和范文&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: University Application</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:06:49 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ -&lt;p&gt;I just helped one of my classmates practice her presentation and watched her present her work. It&amp;rsquo;s an entrance test for a Dutch university and the real thing is coming tomorrow. And it&amp;rsquo;s not simply her presenting to the teachers—she&amp;rsquo;ll present to other applicants, listen to them, talk to them, and the teachers are going to ask her questions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take her a whole morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Dutch university has so many strict entrance requirements. The test covers almost everything that should be taught in their undergraduate course, and the most annoying thing is that they don&amp;rsquo;t give a clear set of criteria. When it comes to grading criteria, I have to admit, the IB is really good. No matter the criteria are good or bad, the IB always gives clear rules about how each assessment should be graded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We just finished our mock exams two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty lost and exhausted, but my lovely classmate had already received her assignment from the university in the middle of the exam week, and had been slowly doing that assignment until now when she is finally close to finishing it. That&amp;rsquo;s such a pain. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think back to my own application season. It was the same—staying up late and having mental breakdowns. Totally relatable.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chinese A Lit: Key Changes for P1 in the 2021 New Syllabus</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 14:53:08 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/&#34;&gt;中文文学 2021 新大纲 P1 变化要点&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 