<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Unless otherwise stated, all works on this blog, 十之以饼干盒 jiaxcuit, are my original works, which are licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License. / 除非特殊声明，本博客（十之以饼干盒 jiaxcuit）中的作品均为原创，并且这些原创作品均遵循知识共享（Creative Commons）署名—非商业性使用—相同方式共享 4.0 公共许可协议国际版。</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 16:44:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IB DP History P2 Revision</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/history-p2-rev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 16:44:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/history-p2-rev/</guid>
      <description>All historical arguments contained or referred to in this article are solely for exam preparation and do not necessarily reflect the view of the author.
Introduction This article includes:
 Steps for IB DP History paper 2 revision; Some extra tips (they can&amp;rsquo;t really fit into the steps); Study resources; My brief essay outlines,  which worked together to help me reach a 7 on paper 2 in my M21 history SL final exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-Term Revision: It&#39;s Okay!</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article includes:
 Short-term revision method My personal experience Online resource  Scenarios suitable for applying this article&amp;rsquo;s method:
 Exam preparation, namely, to improve grades, but not to better your grasp of knowledge Tight schedule (within about a month before the exam?) Plenty of free time  My Experience 0. &amp;ldquo;Cramming&amp;rdquo; and I: Some Unimportant Words? I&amp;rsquo;m a procrastinator, so for many exams, even though I had time to prepare, I still ended up doing short-term preparation, aka cramming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience &amp; Tips for IB Textbooks: History SL</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 18:33:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ib-tb-review-history-sl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the 3rd post in my blog series called &amp;ldquo;My Experience &amp;amp; Tips for IB Textbooks&amp;rdquo;. The IB subjects covered in this series are DP Physics, Math AA, Chemistry, History, and Chinese A Lit. The corresponding levels and syllabus versions (years of first assessment) are as follows:
   Subject Level First Assessment Other Posts in This Series      Physics HL 2016 My Experience &amp;amp; Tips    Math AA HL 2021 My Experience &amp;amp; Tips    Chemistry SL 2016 My Experience &amp;amp; Tips    History SL 2017 This article    Chinese A Lit SL 2021 My Experience &amp;amp; Tips     All of these are the IB DP subjects that I&amp;rsquo;ve studied.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
