<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Short Note on Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/short-note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Short Note on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 17:57:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/short-note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Short Note: Updates</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 17:57:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/thoughts-on-blog-updates/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s a week without any update. The reason is that, I found out with fear and worries that blogging seemed to become a burden instead of an enjoyable hobby for me. When I focused on finishing the series on textbooks, I slowly fell into a trap that I dug for myself—I narrowed my mind to simply doing work and couldn&amp;rsquo;t escape from the whirlpool of endless tasks.
So, I gave myself a break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Note: Excellence or Involution?</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:09:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</guid>
      <description>When neijuan1, or involution, becomes a buzzword and everyone&amp;rsquo;s source of anxiety, when we oppose neijuan and turn to tangping2, are we starting to be complacent with our status quo and even starting to deny excellence?
Today, I bumped into a post of an old classmate on WeChat Moments on this topic. I could really feel her enthusiasm for her subject of studying and her honesty with herself. That honesty is a kind of courage—the courage to recognize her own shortcomings and others&#39; excellence, the courage to stay passionate about her subject and to stay motivated despite challenges and difficulties in her studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Note: Mother Tongue</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:58:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, I was on a team with some students from my school for an online math competition. One of the students on the team (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Student-A) who was from another grade had a Chinese name, so I assumed that she was Chinese or ethnically Chinese. When we met at school, I was &amp;ldquo;relieved&amp;rdquo; to come up and suggest, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk in Chinese!&amp;rdquo; But of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t go well in the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Note: University Application</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:06:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</guid>
      <description>I just helped one of my classmates practice her presentation and watched her present her work. It&amp;rsquo;s an entrance test for a Dutch university and the real thing is coming tomorrow. And it&amp;rsquo;s not simply her presenting to the teachers—she&amp;rsquo;ll present to other applicants, listen to them, talk to them, and the teachers are going to ask her questions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take her a whole morning.
That Dutch university has so many strict entrance requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
