<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study &amp; Organization on Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/categories/study-organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Study &amp; Organization on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Unless otherwise stated, all works on this blog, 十之以饼干盒 jiaxcuit, are my original works, which are licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License. / 除非特殊声明，本博客（十之以饼干盒 jiaxcuit）中的作品均为原创，并且这些原创作品均遵循知识共享（Creative Commons）署名—非商业性使用—相同方式共享 4.0 公共许可协议国际版。</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 20:53:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/categories/study-organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Seat in the Library</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/choosing-a-seat-in-the-library0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 20:53:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/choosing-a-seat-in-the-library0/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to the university library for half a year or so, and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a bit about a tiny thing—choosing a seat.
First of all, nothing is more natural than to make sure that seat is usable, like you need to check that the plugboard, chair, and PC (if any) all work, and so on and so forth. Dont think it&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across plugs that constantly switch the power on and off, chairs with missing wheels that will tilt almost sideways once it&amp;rsquo;s sat on, or those with no soft sponge but only hard metal wires/pipes, and PCs plugged into power but won&amp;rsquo;t turn on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uni Study Log: Measurements &amp; Uncertainties</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-study-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 20:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-study-log/</guid>
      <description>A place to note down where I got extra info on new topics or things that I needed to catch up on.
Also some notes on important ideas.
Poisson distribution The Connection Between the Poisson and Binomial Distributions
Derivation of Poisson distribution from binomial distribution, when the number of trials $n$ is large and the probability of success $p$ is small.
 Introduction to Error Analysis: The Study of Uncertainties in Physical Measurements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Organizing Electronic Files</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-e-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 14:06:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/organizing-e-files/</guid>
      <description>After having to work with many electronic files during my years in the IB, I developed my own file organization method.
Naming Make It Meaningful Give your files meaningful names. It&amp;rsquo;s very likely that you need to revise your essay draft multiple times, so you can&amp;rsquo;t really tell which draft is the final one until you get close to submission. So don&amp;rsquo;t just call it final, and then the revised version real final, and real final final, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-Term Revision: It&#39;s Okay!</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article includes:
 Short-term revision method My personal experience Online resource  Scenarios suitable for applying this article&amp;rsquo;s method:
 Exam preparation, namely, to improve grades, but not to better your grasp of knowledge Tight schedule (within about a month before the exam?) Plenty of free time  My Experience 0. &amp;ldquo;Cramming&amp;rdquo; and I: Some Unimportant Words? I&amp;rsquo;m a procrastinator, so for many exams, even though I had time to prepare, I still ended up doing short-term preparation, aka cramming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 22:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article is on my own note-taking method, which I gradually developed mainly in my 2 years in IB DP, by exploring and experimenting with a range of methods and borrowing from others. During that time, I refused to compromise on the shortcomings in my note-taking method as I continuously tried new methods to arrive at my current set of note-taking methods which satisfies me for now. Together with my current note-taking method, there&amp;rsquo;re some principles of note-taking–my ultimate goal of note-taking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Note: Excellence or Involution?</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:09:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/excellence-or-involution/</guid>
      <description>When neijuan1, or involution, becomes a buzzword and everyone&amp;rsquo;s source of anxiety, when we oppose neijuan and turn to tangping2, are we starting to be complacent with our status quo and even starting to deny excellence?
Today, I bumped into a post of an old classmate on WeChat Moments on this topic. I could really feel her enthusiasm for her subject of studying and her honesty with herself. That honesty is a kind of courage—the courage to recognize her own shortcomings and others&#39; excellence, the courage to stay passionate about her subject and to stay motivated despite challenges and difficulties in her studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus, Habit, Feedback: 3 Tips for Exam Prep</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:17:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</guid>
      <description>Video to Share As the IB exams are approaching, I started to look for a study method more suitable for short term preparation. Just at the same time, Coach_K updated a video on Bilibili about this exact topic. I watched it and thought he indeed had a point, and the video was a great reminder for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here1: CK - How Should You Prepare for Exams? The Powerful Method of a Student Who Scored Nearly Full Marks in SAT (【CK】如何备考？高考近满分学霸的高能方法).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assumptions for an Ideal Transformer</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 12:10:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>Transformers are closely related to induction in the study of electricity and magnetism. Here, I share an article1: Weekly Three Questions - Grade 12: (170) What is &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; for an ideal transformer? (【每周三题】高三【170】理想变压器都“理想”了什么？), by Wu Aixiong (吴爱兄). This article has largely deepened my understanding of transformers.
This article is from Physics Learning Research (物理学习研究), a WeChat Official Account. It posts many other similar articles on physics that investigate into individual topics, including example problems, explanations, and exercises to consolidate knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
