<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study Method on Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/study-method/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Study Method on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:03:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/tags/study-method/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Short-Term Revision: It&#39;s Okay!</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/short-term-rev/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article includes:
 Short-term revision method My personal experience Online resource  Scenarios suitable for applying this article&amp;rsquo;s method:
 Exam preparation, namely, to improve grades, but not to better your grasp of knowledge Tight schedule (within about a month before the exam?) Plenty of free time  My Experience 0. &amp;ldquo;Cramming&amp;rdquo; and I: Some Unimportant Words? I&amp;rsquo;m a procrastinator, so for many exams, even though I had time to prepare, I still ended up doing short-term preparation, aka cramming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 22:04:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article is on my own note-taking method, which I gradually developed mainly in my 2 years in IB DP, by exploring and experimenting with a range of methods and borrowing from others. During that time, I refused to compromise on the shortcomings in my note-taking method as I continuously tried new methods to arrive at my current set of note-taking methods which satisfies me for now. Together with my current note-taking method, there&amp;rsquo;re some principles of note-taking–my ultimate goal of note-taking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus, Habit, Feedback: 3 Tips for Exam Prep</title>
      <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:17:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</guid>
      <description>Video to Share As the IB exams are approaching, I started to look for a study method more suitable for short term preparation. Just at the same time, Coach_K updated a video on Bilibili about this exact topic. I watched it and thought he indeed had a point, and the video was a great reminder for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here1: CK - How Should You Prepare for Exams? The Powerful Method of a Student Who Scored Nearly Full Marks in SAT (【CK】如何备考？高考近满分学霸的高能方法).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
