<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:42:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: University Application</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:06:49 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ -&lt;p&gt;I just helped one of my classmates practice her presentation and watched her present her work. It&amp;rsquo;s an entrance test for a Dutch university and the real thing is coming tomorrow. And it&amp;rsquo;s not simply her presenting to the teachers—she&amp;rsquo;ll present to other applicants, listen to them, talk to them, and the teachers are going to ask her questions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take her a whole morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Dutch university has so many strict entrance requirements. The test covers almost everything that should be taught in their undergraduate course, and the most annoying thing is that they don&amp;rsquo;t give a clear set of criteria. When it comes to grading criteria, I have to admit, the IB is really good. No matter the criteria are good or bad, the IB always gives clear rules about how each assessment should be graded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We just finished our mock exams two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty lost and exhausted, but my lovely classmate had already received her assignment from the university in the middle of the exam week, and had been slowly doing that assignment until now when she is finally close to finishing it. That&amp;rsquo;s such a pain. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think back to my own application season. It was the same—staying up late and having mental breakdowns. Totally relatable.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chinese A Lit: Key Changes for P1 in the 2021 New Syllabus</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 14:53:08 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/&#34;&gt;中文文学 2021 新大纲 P1 变化要点&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 