<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiaxcuit</title>
    <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiaxcuit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: Mother Tongue</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:58:34 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/ -&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was on a team with some students from my school for an online math competition. One of the students on the team (let&amp;rsquo;s call her Student-A) who was from another grade had a Chinese name, so I assumed that she was Chinese or ethnically Chinese. When we met at school, I was &amp;ldquo;relieved&amp;rdquo; to come up and suggest, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk in Chinese!&amp;rdquo; But of course it didn&amp;rsquo;t go well in the reality. Having heard my words, Student-A smiled awkwardly and said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at Chinese.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, Student-A spoke Chinese with me that day. We also spoke Chinese during the preparation right before the competition, when it was just the two of us talking. Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there was anything wrong with her Chinese—I was even a little surprised that she knew the Chinese word for a math terminology like calculus. So, I speculated as I apologized for my rudeness in my mind: Is she so used to hearing people say she is not good at Chinese that she is not confident in herself? I thought she was excellent and she probably knew a lot of Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, when other team members were there, we just talked in English. After the competition, when only the two of us talked together, we also used English. I have to say, shamefully, that when talking about topics related to our school and school work, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a little less stumbling if I use English. I also tried to find excuses for myself: If I talked to with Student-A in English, she would actually be more comfortable, right? We didn&amp;rsquo;t really know each other before, so I should&amp;rsquo;ve been more considerate of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, but—I do understand English, yet English is not &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in an international school for a few years now, and I have never forgotten my mother tongue. I feel proud and lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proud that I have been listening and reading in my mother tongue. I am proud that I have been working hard to learn IB Chinese literature. I am proud that I have been writing in my native language even outside of class (not at a particularly great level though 😅). Because of all these things, I could see a wider world and convey my thoughts to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky that my family did not make me leave my native language environment in grade 7, grade 8, or even in primary, so I could be immersed in an environment where teaching and instructions are in Chinese for a few more years. However, some of my friends left home early, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if they continued to learn their mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to criticize anyone, let alone despise anyone&lt;/strong&gt;. There are so many reasons for leaving a native language environment, and many of the reasons involve things that are simply out of personal control. Actually, I admire my friends who left home early, became independent quickly, and gradually adapted to their new environments. Moreover, I truly aspire to their excellence and mental strength. Based on my own experience, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to leave a native language environment and adapt to a new one. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the same for them. After all, a person&amp;rsquo;s mother tongue is closely related to his/her identity and culture, which are probably deeply rooted in everyone&amp;rsquo;s heart. Not everyone is the same as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/04/01/andrew-yang-coronavirus-discrimination/&#34;&gt;some ridiculous politicians&lt;/a&gt; who are ashamed of their identity all day long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might sound condescending, but I still feel deeply sorry for those who have consciously or accidentally forgotten their native language, or those whose mother tongue skills have largely declined. Like many people, I was once lost and confused. I once thought, &amp;ldquo;How wonderful it would be if my mother tongue was English?&amp;rdquo; And I wanted to learn English to a native level. But what about Chinese&amp;hellip;? I thought at the time, it probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore. However, I slowly, slowly realized that knowing Chinese is really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized this because of one of my teachers. Once, she happened to learn that I read Chinese textbooks in addition to English textbooks. Unexpectedly, she immediately yelled out with great excitement, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s fantastic! I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that you could read academic materials in Chinese! That&amp;rsquo;s really, really great.&amp;rdquo; It was only then that I realized reading academic materials in Chinese was a skill. It was so late for me to realize. I had always benefited from knowing Chinese, but had never recognized its importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also realized something more. When I read the delicate and thoughtful literature works in my IB Chinese literature class, when I feel the subtleties in the tiny details of the texts, when I write down what I see, hear and feel in Chinese freely, I start to feel something much more precious than the practical value of the Chinese language—Chinese has allowed me to enjoy the beauty of language and literature with the most genuine emotional experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of mother tongues, I remember a classmate I met in my German language class, Classmate-B. Classmate-B is a dual citizen of the US and Germany. She said that her father was German, but her father never taught her German, and she didn&amp;rsquo;t know why. Having grown up in the US, Classmate-B naturally speaks English on a daily basis. English should have been enough for her, because after all, it is a world language. But she still came to Germany and stayed with her German-speaking uncle to learn German. She wanted to apply for a German university after she leaves school, because universities in Germany are free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German could have been a mother tongue for Classmate-B, and she could have learned it naturally, little by little, as she grew up. But now, she needs to put in the extra effort to learn it. I guess, German would still be a foreign language for her, instead of &lt;strong&gt;her&lt;/strong&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask me: What are the benefits of learning your mother tongue? I think, even in the most utilitarian sense, it would avoid troubles such as Classmate-B&amp;rsquo;s. Not to mention the spiritual wealth that comes from mastering your mother tongue, which is truly priceless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese is my mother tongue, &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; language. In an international environment, I am still able to use my mother tongue. I am proud of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is not &amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo; anymore 😂 But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start a new series for now, and I don&amp;rsquo;t bother coming up with a name for a new series, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it as it is. There are lots of thoughts, but my honest thoughts. Thank you for reading this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &amp;ldquo;a language that I understand&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;my language&amp;rdquo; many times in the article. That was inspired by a poster in a German classroom at our school. The original (mis)quote&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on the poster was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you talk to a man in a language he understands, that goes to his head. If you talk to him in his language, that goes to his heart.
—Nelson Mandela&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.harvard.edu/pierredegalbert/node/632263&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by researcher Pierre de Galbert to learn some interesting background stories behind the quote.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/mother-tongue/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Friends</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 04:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/ -&lt;p&gt;I will be posting links to some of my friends&#39; blogs here from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s really a nice coincidence that we are meeting each other on the internet. Since you are already here, you might as well check out these blogs too 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ib-land.netlify.app&#34;&gt;IB Land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my friend Violet&amp;rsquo;s blog in English, mainly sharing her IB learning experience and study methods. She&amp;rsquo;s really great! And she really has a lot of experience in IB because she went through IB PYP, MYP and DP. That&amp;rsquo;s the whole of IB system.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/friends/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Focus, Habit, Feedback: 3 Tips for Exam Prep</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:17:59 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-to-share&#34;&gt;Video to Share&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the IB exams are approaching, I started to look for a study method more suitable for short term preparation. Just at the same time, Coach_K updated a video on Bilibili about this exact topic. I watched it and thought he indeed had a point, and the video was a great reminder for me, so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1oZ4y1w76F?share_source=copy_web&#34;&gt;CK - How Should You Prepare for Exams? The Powerful Method of a Student Who Scored Nearly Full Marks in SAT&lt;/a&gt; (【CK】如何备考？高考近满分学霸的高能方法). The video lasts for 8 min 50 s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K is really excellent and he&amp;rsquo;s a treasure-like uploader whom I&amp;rsquo;ve been following for a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about him again when I share time management methods and more study methods in the future. If you are interested, you can check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://space.bilibili.com/474571157/video&#34;&gt;Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s other videos&lt;/a&gt; on Bilibili&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;key-points&#34;&gt;Key Points&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K brings up 3 points in the video: &lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Habit&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;, in the order of increasing importance. He points out that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on your task allows us to accomplish more in a short period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Habits allow us to save energy by reducing the number of unnecessary decisions we need to make and reducing the effort we put into making those decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback allows us to check for and fill in the gaps in our knowledge. It also allows us to improve our strategy and tactics for doing practice problems, so that we can make the most out of each problem we do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking about &amp;ldquo;feedback&amp;rdquo;, Coach_K emphasized the importance of &lt;strong&gt;reflection&lt;/strong&gt;. Reflection means looking back at a problem that we did wrong, finding the reason why we made the mistake, suggesting a solution to the situation, and starting to improve based on the solution right away. As he said, reflection is indeed a painful process, but if we just do problems without analyzing why we make mistakes and without improving specifically in our weaker areas, we are just creating an illusion that we are trying, which is a waste of our time and energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s point about habits was something I had never realized. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At school, when I follow a set schedule and have a teacher leading my revision, I get clear instructions, so I everything&amp;rsquo;s clear and I can revise without worrying much. At home, when I have to plan my daily revision, I get annoyed a lot by numerous small things: what paper I should do today, when I should do it, how long I should spend on it, and even smaller things such as what to eat for lunch and when to wash up. All of these trivial things require me to invest my energy to make decisions, reducing the amount of energy I have for exam preparation. These tedious and trivial tasks would affect me much less if I could &amp;ldquo;mindlessly&amp;rdquo; follow a schedule to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The similarity between Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s video and my previous thinking is that &amp;lsquo;reflection&amp;rsquo; is painful but necessary. After listening to his summary, my own thoughts also became clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current history teacher never goes over our tests or exams with us in class. He lets us look at his written feedback and annotations on the papers on our own, and if we have questions, he asks us to approach him individually and talk to him one-on-one. This form of teaching gave us a lot of freedom, but because of this, I often did the papers, got them graded, put them aside, and never touched them again. Practically, I could always go back to review the exam papers. It didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter when I do that. So I allocated my limited time to more important and more urgent tasks in other subjects. Psychologically, I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t dare to look at my own mistakes. Reviewing one&amp;rsquo;s own exam papers is indeed painful and must take a lot of effort. But when I actually picked up my exam papers and reviewed them word by word, and when I compared my answer with the model answer to see why exactly I lost marks, I did learn a lot and made huge progress. In my previous study process, I always skipped the reflection step. That&amp;rsquo;s why I got stuck with my grade in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I summarized the three tips for exam preparation in Coach_K&amp;rsquo;s video on Bilibili, which are focus, habit, and feedback. Then, I briefly cleared up my thoughts with reference to my own learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post only mentions that reflection is painful, but in fact, I know that not only is reflection painful, but learning (or any work you do that gives actual output) is also painful. Or, to be more precise, it is &lt;strong&gt;energy consuming&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing more resources on learning methods on this blog later, and I&amp;rsquo;ll expand on this point as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, feel free to discuss or share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video is in Chinese.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His videos are in Chinese, and the video platform Bilibili is also in Chinese (except for the Investor Relations section 😂).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/focus-habit-feedback-last-min-study-tips/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Assumptions for an Ideal Transformer</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 12:10:42 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/ -&lt;p&gt;Transformers are closely related to induction in the study of electricity and magnetism. Here, I share an article&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/T0DcwTlz0DYTKsijbmVpBA&#34;&gt;Weekly Three Questions - Grade 12: (170) What is &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; for an ideal transformer?&lt;/a&gt; (【每周三题】高三【170】理想变压器都“理想”了什么？), by Wu Aixiong (吴爱兄). This article has largely deepened my understanding of transformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is from &lt;strong&gt;Physics Learning Research&lt;/strong&gt; (物理学习研究), a WeChat Official Account. It posts many other similar articles on physics that investigate into individual topics, including example problems, explanations, and exercises to consolidate knowledge. Most of the content is high quality and is suitable for students from grade 9 to grade 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explains the &lt;strong&gt;components&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;theoretical principles&lt;/strong&gt; of a transformer, and then explains the &lt;strong&gt;assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; of an ideal transformer. The article also discusses in detail the various &lt;strong&gt;conclusions&lt;/strong&gt; regarding transformers, such as the conditions for $\frac{\epsilon_1}{\epsilon_2} = \frac{V_1}{V_2}$ to be true. The article covers topics such as &lt;strong&gt;inductive reactance&lt;/strong&gt; which is not covered in IB physics, but it is mentioned less frequently in the article and only appears at the very end. The four exercises in the article are helpful as they closely relate to the content in IB Physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that due to formatting issues, the first part of question (1) is centered below the first picture, however it is not a caption of the picture, so be careful not to think it is the caption or miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading! I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher but just an IB student who has bits of thoughts. If you have more thoughts and insights, you are welcome to share them here! (Also look for contact information at the end of the &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; section of this blog.) I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about what other people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article is in Chinese.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/ideal-transformer-assumptions/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chinese A Lit: P1 Skills &amp; Exemplars</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 15:05:52 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do 😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/&#34;&gt;中文文学 P1 写作方法和范文&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-skills-online-resources/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Short Note: University Application</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 15:06:49 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ -&lt;p&gt;I just helped one of my classmates practice her presentation and watched her present her work. It&amp;rsquo;s an entrance test for a Dutch university and the real thing is coming tomorrow. And it&amp;rsquo;s not simply her presenting to the teachers—she&amp;rsquo;ll present to other applicants, listen to them, talk to them, and the teachers are going to ask her questions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take her a whole morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Dutch university has so many strict entrance requirements. The test covers almost everything that should be taught in their undergraduate course, and the most annoying thing is that they don&amp;rsquo;t give a clear set of criteria. When it comes to grading criteria, I have to admit, the IB is really good. No matter the criteria are good or bad, the IB always gives clear rules about how each assessment should be graded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We just finished our mock exams two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty lost and exhausted, but my lovely classmate had already received her assignment from the university in the middle of the exam week, and had been slowly doing that assignment until now when she is finally close to finishing it. That&amp;rsquo;s such a pain. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think back to my own application season. It was the same—staying up late and having mental breakdowns. Totally relatable.&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/uni-app/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chinese A Lit: Key Changes for P1 in the 2021 New Syllabus</title>
        <link>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 14:53:08 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/</guid>
        <description>Jiaxcuit //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ -&lt;p&gt;Thank you for clicking on this blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re doing Chinese A Lit, then I assume you understand Chinese quite well. (And I hope you do 😂) So here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the same post in Chinese (Simplified): &lt;a href=&#34;https://jiaxcuit.github.io/zh/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/&#34;&gt;中文文学 2021 新大纲 P1 变化要点&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts or comments are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
- //jiaxcuit.github.io/en/posts/p1-syllabus-changes/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 